[{"num":1,"sample":"1A11","correct":"A","question":"The product of the readings of an AC voltmeter and AC ammeter is called: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tApparent power. ","b":"B.\tTrue power. ","c":"C.\tPower factor. ","d":"D.\tCurrent power"}},{"num":2,"sample":"1A12","correct":"B","question":"What is the basic unit of electrical power? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tOhm. ","b":"B.\tWatt. ","c":"C.\tVolt. ","d":"D.\tAmpere"}},{"num":3,"sample":"1A13","correct":"A","question":"What is the term used to express the amount of electrical energy stored in an electrostatic field? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tJoules. ","b":"B.\tCoulombs. ","c":"C.\tWatts. ","d":"D.\tVolts"}},{"num":4,"sample":"1A14","correct":"C","question":"What device is used to store electrical energy in an electrostatic field? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBattery. ","b":"B.\tTransformer. ","c":"C.\tCapacitor. ","d":"D.\tInductor"}},{"num":5,"sample":"1A15","correct":"B","question":"What formula would determine the inductive reactance of a coil if frequency and coil inductance are known? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tXL = &pi;f L . ","b":"B.\tXL = 2&pi;f L . ","c":"C.\tXL = 1 / 2&pi;f C. ","d":"D.\tXL = 1 / R2+X2"}},{"num":6,"sample":"1A16","correct":"D","question":"What is the term for the out-of-phase power associated with inductors and capacitors? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tEffective power. ","b":"B.\tTrue power. ","c":"C.\tPeak envelope power. ","d":"D.\tReactive power"}},{"num":7,"sample":"1A21","correct":"D","question":"What determines the strength of the magnetic field around a conductor? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe resistance divided by the current. ","b":"B.\tThe ratio of the current to the resistance. ","c":"C.\tThe diameter of the conductor. ","d":"D.\tThe amount of current"}},{"num":8,"sample":"1A22","correct":"C","question":"What will produce a magnetic field? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA DC source not connected to a circuit. ","b":"B.\tThe presence of a voltage across a capacitor. ","c":"C.\tA current flowing through a conductor. ","d":"D.\tThe force that drives current through a resistor"}},{"num":9,"sample":"1A23","correct":"A","question":"When induced currents produce expanding magnetic fields around conductors in a direction that opposes the original magnetic field, this is known as: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tLenz's law. ","b":"B.\tGilbert's law. ","c":"C.\tMaxwell's law. ","d":"D.\tNorton's law"}},{"num":10,"sample":"1A24","correct":"D","question":"The opposition to the creation of magnetic lines of force in a magnetic circuit is known as: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tEddy currents. ","b":"B.\tHysteresis. ","c":"C.\tPermeability. ","d":"D.\tReluctance"}},{"num":11,"sample":"1A25","correct":"C","question":"What is meant by the term 'back EMF'? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA current equal to the applied EMF. ","b":"B.\tAn opposing EMF equal to R times C (RC) percent of the applied EMF. ","c":"C.\tA voltage that opposes the applied EMF. ","d":"D.\tA current that opposes the applied EMF"}},{"num":12,"sample":"1A26","correct":"B","question":"Permeability is defined as: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe magnetic field created by a conductor wound on a laminated core and carrying current. ","b":"B.\tThe ratio of magnetic flux density in a substance to the magnetizing force that produces it. ","c":"C.\tPolarized molecular alignment in a ferromagnetic material while under the influence of a magnetizing force. ","d":"D.\tNone of these"}},{"num":13,"sample":"1A31","correct":"C","question":"What metal is usually employed as a sacrificial anode for corrosion control purposes? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tPlatinum bushing. ","b":"B.\tLead bar. ","c":"C.\tZinc bar. ","d":"D.\tBrass rod"}},{"num":14,"sample":"1A32","correct":"A","question":"What is the relative dielectric constant for air? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1. ","b":"B.\t2. ","c":"C.\t4. ","d":"D.\t0"}},{"num":15,"sample":"1A33","correct":"D","question":"Which metal object may be least affected by galvanic corrosion when submerged in seawater? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAluminum outdrive. ","b":"B.\tBronze through-hull. ","c":"C.\tExposed lead keel. ","d":"D.\tStainless steel propeller shaft"}},{"num":16,"sample":"1A34","correct":"A","question":"Skin effect is the phenomenon where: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tRF current flows in a thin layer of the conductor, closer to the surface, as frequency increases. ","b":"B.\tRF current flows in a thin layer of the conductor, closer to the surface, as frequency decreases. ","c":"C.\tThermal effects on the surface of the conductor increase the impedance. ","d":"D.\tThermal effects on the surface of the conductor decrease the impedance"}},{"num":17,"sample":"1A35","correct":"D","question":"Corrosion resulting from electric current flow between dissimilar metals is called: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tElectrolysis. ","b":"B.\tStray current corrosion. ","c":"C.\tOxygen starvation corrosion. ","d":"D.\tGalvanic corrosion"}},{"num":18,"sample":"1A36","correct":"B","question":"Which of these will be most useful for insulation at UHF frequencies? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tRubber. ","b":"B.\tMica. ","c":"C.\tWax impregnated paper. ","d":"D.\tLead"}},{"num":19,"sample":"1A41","correct":"B","question":"What formula would calculate the total inductance of inductors in series? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tLT = L1 / L2. ","b":"B.\tLT = L1 + L2. ","c":"C.\tLT = 1 / L1 + L2. ","d":"D.\tLT = 1 / L1 x L2"}},{"num":20,"sample":"1A42","correct":"D","question":"Good conductors with minimum resistance have what type of electrons? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tFew free electrons. ","b":"B.\tNo electrons. ","c":"C.\tSome free electrons. ","d":"D.\tMany free electrons"}},{"num":21,"sample":"1A43","correct":"A","question":"Which of the 4 groups of metals listed below are the best low-resistance conductors? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tGold, silver, and copper. ","b":"B.\tStainless steel, bronze, and lead. ","c":"C.\tIron, lead, and nickel. ","d":"D.\tBronze, zinc, and manganese"}},{"num":22,"sample":"1A44","correct":"C","question":"What is the purpose of a bypass capacitor? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIt increases the resonant frequency of the circuit. ","b":"B.\tIt removes direct current from the circuit by shunting DC to ground. ","c":"C.\tIt removes alternating current by providing a low impedance path to ground. ","d":"D.\tIt forms part of an impedance transforming circuit"}},{"num":23,"sample":"1A45","correct":"B","question":"How would you calculate the total capacitance of three capacitors in parallel? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tCT = C1 + C2 / C1 - C2 + C3. ","b":"B.\tCT = C1 + C2 + C3. ","c":"C.\tCT = C1 + C2 / C1 x C2 + C3. ","d":"D.\tCT = 1 / C1+1 / C2 + 1 / C3"}},{"num":24,"sample":"1A46","correct":"C","question":"How might you reduce the inductance of an antenna coil? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAdd additional turns. ","b":"B.\tAdd more core permeability. ","c":"C.\tReduce the number of turns. ","d":"D.\tCompress the coil turns"}},{"num":25,"sample":"1A51","correct":"D","question":"What are the two most commonly-used specifications for a junction diode? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tMaximum forward current and capacitance. ","b":"B.\tMaximum reverse current and PIV (peak inverse voltage). ","c":"C.\tMaximum reverse current and capacitance. ","d":"D.\tMaximum forward current and PIV (peak inverse voltage)"}},{"num":26,"sample":"1A52","correct":"B","question":"What limits the maximum forward current in a junction diode? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe peak inverse voltage (PIV). ","b":"B.\tThe junction temperature. ","c":"C.\tThe forward voltage. ","d":"D.\tThe back EMF"}},{"num":27,"sample":"1A53","correct":"C","question":"MOSFETs are manufactured with THIS protective device built into their gate to protect the device from static charges and excessive voltages: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tSchottky diode. ","b":"B.\tMetal oxide varistor (MOV). ","c":"C.\tZener diode. ","d":"D.\tTunnel diode"}},{"num":28,"sample":"1A54","correct":"A","question":"What are the two basic types of junction field-effect transistors? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tN-channel and P-channel. ","b":"B.\tHigh power and low power. ","c":"C.\tMOSFET and GaAsFET. ","d":"D.\tSilicon FET and germanium FET"}},{"num":29,"sample":"1A55","correct":"B","question":"A common emitter amplifier has: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tLower input impedance than a common base. ","b":"B.\tMore voltage gain than a common collector. ","c":"C.\tLess current gain than a common base. ","d":"D.\tLess voltage gain than a common collector"}},{"num":30,"sample":"1A56","correct":"A","question":"How does the input impedance of a field-effect transistor compare with that of a bipolar transistor? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAn FET has high input impedance; a bipolar transistor has low input impedance. ","b":"B.\tOne cannot compare input impedance without first knowing the supply voltage. ","c":"C.\tAn FET has low input impedance; a bipolar transistor has high input impedance. ","d":"D.\tThe input impedance of FETs and bipolar transistors is the same"}},{"num":31,"sample":"1A61","correct":"B","question":"An AC ammeter indicates: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tEffective (TRM) values of current. ","b":"B.\tEffective (RMS) values of current. ","c":"C.\tPeak values of current. ","d":"D.\tAverage values of current"}},{"num":32,"sample":"1A62","correct":"C","question":"By what factor must the voltage of an AC circuit, as indicated on the scale of an AC voltmeter, be multiplied to obtain the peak voltage value? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t0.707. ","b":"B.\t0.9. ","c":"C.\t1.414. ","d":"D.\t3.14"}},{"num":33,"sample":"1A63","correct":"D","question":"What is the RMS voltage at a common household electrical power outlet? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t331-V AC. ","b":"B.\t82.7-V AC. ","c":"C.\t165.5-V AC. ","d":"D.\t117-V AC"}},{"num":34,"sample":"1A64","correct":"A","question":"What is the easiest voltage amplitude to measure by viewing a pure sine wave signal on an oscilloscope? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tPeak-to-peak. ","b":"B.\tRMS. ","c":"C.\tAverage. ","d":"D.\tDC"}},{"num":35,"sample":"1A65","correct":"C","question":"By what factor must the voltage measured in an AC circuit, as indicated on the scale of an AC voltmeter, be multiplied to obtain the average voltage value? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t0.707. ","b":"B.\t1.414. ","c":"C.\t0.9. ","d":"D.\t3.14"}},{"num":36,"sample":"1A66","correct":"D","question":"What is the peak voltage at a common household electrical outlet? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t234 volts. ","b":"B.\t117 volts. ","c":"C.\t331 volts. ","d":"D.\t165.5 volts"}},{"num":37,"sample":"1A71","correct":"B","question":"What is a sine wave? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA constant-voltage, varying-current wave. ","b":"B.\tA wave whose amplitude at any given instant can be represented by the projection of a point on a wheel rotating at a uniform speed. ","c":"C.\tA wave following the laws of the trigonometric tangent function. ","d":"D.\tA wave whose polarity changes in a random manner"}},{"num":38,"sample":"1A72","correct":"D","question":"How many degrees are there in one complete sine wave cycle? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t90 degrees. ","b":"B.\t270 degrees. ","c":"C.\t180 degrees. ","d":"D.\t360 degrees"}},{"num":39,"sample":"1A73","correct":"A","question":"What type of wave is made up of sine waves of the fundamental frequency and all the odd harmonics? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tSquare. ","b":"B.\tSine. ","c":"C.\tCosine. ","d":"D.\tTangent"}},{"num":40,"sample":"1A74","correct":"D","question":"What is the description of a square wave? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA wave with only 300 degrees in one cycle. ","b":"B.\tA wave whose periodic function is always negative. ","c":"C.\tA wave whose periodic function is always positive. ","d":"D.\tA wave that abruptly changes back and forth between two voltage levels and stays at these levels for equal amounts of time"}},{"num":41,"sample":"1A75","correct":"A","question":"What type of wave is made up of sine waves at the fundamental frequency and all the harmonics? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tSawtooth wave. ","b":"B.\tSquare wave. ","c":"C.\tSine wave. ","d":"D.\tCosine wave"}},{"num":42,"sample":"1A76","correct":"C","question":"What type of wave is characterized by a rise time significantly faster than the fall time (or vice versa)? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tCosine wave. ","b":"B.\tSquare wave. ","c":"C.\tSawtooth wave. ","d":"D.\tSine wave"}},{"num":43,"sample":"1A81","correct":"C","question":"What is the term used to identify an AC voltage that would cause the same heating in a resistor as a corresponding value of DC voltage? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tCosine voltage. ","b":"B.\tPower factor. ","c":"C.\tRoot mean square (RMS). ","d":"D.\tAverage voltage"}},{"num":44,"sample":"1A82","correct":"B","question":"What happens to reactive power in a circuit that has both inductors and capacitors? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIt is dissipated as heat in the circuit. ","b":"B.\tIt alternates between magnetic and electric fields and is not dissipated. ","c":"C.\tIt is dissipated as inductive and capacitive fields. ","d":"D.\tIt is dissipated as kinetic energy within the circuit"}},{"num":45,"sample":"1A83","correct":"C","question":"Halving the cross-sectional area of a conductor will: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tNot affect the resistance. ","b":"B.\tQuarter the resistance. ","c":"C.\tDouble the resistance. ","d":"D.\tHalve the resistance"}},{"num":46,"sample":"1A84","correct":"A","question":"Which of the following groups is correct for listing common materials in order of descending conductivity? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tSilver, copper, aluminum, iron, and lead. ","b":"B.\tLead, iron, silver, aluminum, and copper. ","c":"C.\tIron, silver, aluminum, copper, and silver. ","d":"D.\tSilver, aluminum, iron, lead, and copper"}},{"num":47,"sample":"1A85","correct":"D","question":"How do you compute true power (power dissipated in the circuit) in a circuit where AC voltage and current are out of phase? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tMultiply RMS voltage times RMS current. ","b":"B.\tSubtract apparent power from the power factor. ","c":"C.\tDivide apparent power by the power factor. ","d":"D.\tMultiply apparent power times the power factor"}},{"num":48,"sample":"1A86","correct":"B","question":"Assuming a power source to have a fixed value of internal resistance, maximum power will be transferred to the load when: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe load impedance is greater than the source impedance. ","b":"B.\tThe load impedance equals the internal impedance of the source. ","c":"C.\tThe load impedance is less than the source impedance. ","d":"D.\tThe fixed values of internal impedance are not relative to the power source"}},{"num":49,"sample":"1B91","correct":"A","question":"What value of series resistor would be needed to obtain a full scale deflection on a 50 microamp DC meter with an applied voltage of 200 volts DC? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t4 megohms. ","b":"B.\t2 megohms. ","c":"C.\t400 kilohms. ","d":"D.\t200 kilohms"}},{"num":50,"sample":"1B92","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following Ohms Law formulas is incorrect? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tI = E / R. ","b":"B.\tI = R / E. ","c":"C.\tE = I x R. ","d":"D.\tR = E / I"}},{"num":51,"sample":"1B93","correct":"D","question":"If a current of 2 amperes flows through a 50-ohm resistor, what is the voltage across the resistor? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t25 volts. ","b":"B.\t52 volts. ","c":"C.\t200 volts. ","d":"D.\t100 volts"}},{"num":52,"sample":"1B94","correct":"A","question":"If a 100-ohm resistor is connected across 200 volts, what is the current through the resistor? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t2 amperes. ","b":"B.\t1 ampere. ","c":"C.\t300 amperes. ","d":"D.\t20,000 amperes"}},{"num":53,"sample":"1B95","correct":"B","question":"If a current of 3 amperes flows through a resistor connected to 90 volts, what is the resistance? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t3 ohms. ","b":"B.\t30 ohms. ","c":"C.\t93 ohms. ","d":"D.\t270 ohms"}},{"num":54,"sample":"1B96","correct":"C","question":"A relay coil has 500 ohms resistance, and operates on 125 mA. What value of resistance should be connected in series with it to operate from 110 V DC? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t150 ohms. ","b":"B.\t220 ohms. ","c":"C.\t380 ohms. ","d":"D.\t470 ohms"}},{"num":55,"sample":"1B101","correct":"D","question":"What is the peak-to-peak RF voltage on the 50 ohm output of a 100 watt transmitter? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t70 volts. ","b":"B.\t100 volts. ","c":"C.\t140 volts. ","d":"D.\t200 volts"}},{"num":56,"sample":"1B102","correct":"C","question":"What is the maximum DC or RMS voltage that may be connected across a 20 watt, 2000 ohm resistor? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t10 volts. ","b":"B.\t100 volts. ","c":"C.\t200 volts. ","d":"D.\t10,000 volts"}},{"num":57,"sample":"1B103","correct":"B","question":"A 500-ohm, 2-watt resistor and a 1500-ohm, 1-watt resistor are connected in parallel.  What is the maximum voltage that can be applied across the parallel circuit without exceeding wattage ratings? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t22.4 volts. ","b":"B.\t31.6 volts. ","c":"C.\t38.7 volts. ","d":"D.\t875 volts"}},{"num":58,"sample":"1B104","correct":"C","question":"In Figure 3B1, what is the voltage drop across R1? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t9 volts. ","b":"B.\t7 volts. ","c":"C.\t5 volts. ","d":"D.\t3 volts"}},{"num":59,"sample":"1B105","correct":"D","question":"In Figure 3B2, what is the voltage drop across R1? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1.2 volts. ","b":"B.\t2.4 volts. ","c":"C.\t3.7 volts. ","d":"D.\t9 volts"}},{"num":60,"sample":"1B106","correct":"A","question":"What is the maximum rated current-carrying capacity of a resistor marked '2000 ohms, 200 watts'? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t0.316 amps. ","b":"B.\t3.16 amps. ","c":"C.\t10 amps. ","d":"D.\t100 amps"}},{"num":61,"sample":"1B111","correct":"A","question":"What is the most the actual transmit frequency could differ from a reading of 462,100,000 Hertz on a frequency counter with a time base accuracy of &plusmn; 0.1 ppm? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t46.21 Hz. ","b":"B.\t0.1 MHz. ","c":"C.\t462.1 Hz. ","d":"D.\t0.2 MHz"}},{"num":62,"sample":"1B112","correct":"B","question":"The second harmonic of a 380 kHz frequency is: ","answers":{"a":"A.\t2 MHz. ","b":"B.\t760 kHz. ","c":"C.\t190 kHz. ","d":"D.\t144.4 GHz"}},{"num":63,"sample":"1B113","correct":"A","question":"What is the second harmonic of SSB frequency 4146 kHz? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t8292 kHz. ","b":"B.\t4.146 MHz. ","c":"C.\t2073 kHz. ","d":"D.\t12438 kHz"}},{"num":64,"sample":"1B114","correct":"C","question":"What is the most the actual transmitter frequency could differ from a reading of 156,520,000 hertz on a frequency counter with a time base accuracy of &plusmn; 1.0 ppm? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t165.2 Hz. ","b":"B.\t15.652 kHz. ","c":"C.\t156.52 Hz. ","d":"D.\t1.4652 MHz"}},{"num":65,"sample":"1B115","correct":"B","question":"What is the most the actual transmitter frequency could differ from a reading of 156,520,000 Hertz on a frequency counter with a time base accuracy of +/- 10 ppm? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t146.52 Hz. ","b":"B.\t1565.20 Hz. ","c":"C.\t10 Hz. ","d":"D.\t156.52 kHz"}},{"num":66,"sample":"1B116","correct":"D","question":"What is the most the actual transmitter frequency could differ from a reading of 462,100,000 hertz on a frequency counter with a time base accuracy of &plusmn; 1.0 ppm? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t46.21 MHz. ","b":"B.\t10 Hz. ","c":"C.\t1.0 MHz. ","d":"D.\t462.1 Hz"}},{"num":67,"sample":"1B121","correct":"D","question":"At pi/3 radians, what is the amplitude of a sine-wave having a peak value of 5 volts? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t-4.3 volts. ","b":"B.\t-2.5 volts. ","c":"C.\t+2.5 volts. ","d":"D.\t+4.3 volts"}},{"num":68,"sample":"1B122","correct":"C","question":"At 150 degrees, what is the amplitude of a sine-wave having a peak value of 5 volts? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t-4.3 volts. ","b":"B.\t-2.5 volts. ","c":"C.\t+2.5 volts. ","d":"D.\t+4.3 volts"}},{"num":69,"sample":"1B123","correct":"A","question":"At 240 degrees, what is the amplitude of a sine-wave having a peak value of 5 volts? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t-4.3 volts. ","b":"B.\t-2.5 volts. ","c":"C.\t+2.5 volts. ","d":"D.\t+4.3 volts"}},{"num":70,"sample":"1B124","correct":"D","question":"What is the equivalent to the root-mean-square value of an AC voltage? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAC voltage is the square root of the average AC value. ","b":"B.\tThe DC voltage causing the same heating in a given resistor at the peak AC voltage. ","c":"C.\tThe AC voltage found by taking the square of the average value of the peak AC voltage. ","d":"D.\tThe DC voltage causing the same heating in a given resistor as the RMS AC voltage of the same value"}},{"num":71,"sample":"1B125","correct":"C","question":"What is the RMS value of a 340-volt peak-to-peak pure sine wave? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t170 volts AC. ","b":"B.\t240 volts AC. ","c":"C.\t120 volts AC. ","d":"D.\t350 volts AC"}},{"num":72,"sample":"1B126","correct":"B","question":"Determine the phase relationship between the two signals shown in Figure 3B3. ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA is lagging B by 90 degrees. ","b":"B.\tB is lagging A by 90 degrees. ","c":"C.\tA is leading B by 180 degrees. ","d":"D.\tB is leading A by 90 degrees"}},{"num":73,"sample":"1B131","correct":"C","question":"What does the power factor equal in an R-L circuit having a 60 degree phase angle between the voltage and the current? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t0.414. ","b":"B.\t0.866. ","c":"C.\t0.5. ","d":"D.\t1.73"}},{"num":74,"sample":"1B132","correct":"A","question":"If a resistance to which a constant voltage is applied is halved, what power dissipation will result? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tDouble. ","b":"B.\tHalved. ","c":"C.\tQuadruple. ","d":"D.\tRemain the same"}},{"num":75,"sample":"1B133","correct":"D","question":"746 watts, corresponding to the lifting of 550 pounds at the rate of one-foot-per-second, is the equivalent of how much horsepower? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tOne-quarter horsepower. ","b":"B.\tOne-half horsepower. ","c":"C.\tThree-quarters horsepower. ","d":"D.\tOne horsepower"}},{"num":76,"sample":"1B134","correct":"A","question":"In a circuit where the AC voltage and current are out of phase, how can the true power be determined? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBy multiplying the apparent power times the power factor. ","b":"B.\tBy subtracting the apparent power from the power factor. ","c":"C.\tBy dividing the apparent power by the power factor. ","d":"D.\tBy multiplying the RMS voltage times the RMS current"}},{"num":77,"sample":"1B135","correct":"D","question":"What does the power factor equal in an R-L circuit having a 45 degree phase angle between the voltage and the current? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t0.866. ","b":"B.\t1.0. ","c":"C.\t0.5. ","d":"D.\t0.707"}},{"num":78,"sample":"1B136","correct":"B","question":"What does the power factor equal in an R-L circuit having a 30 degree phase angle between the voltage and the current? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1.73. ","b":"B.\t0.866. ","c":"C.\t0.5. ","d":"D.\t0.577"}},{"num":79,"sample":"1B141","correct":"B","question":"What is the term for the time required for the capacitor in an RC circuit to be charged to 63.2% of the supply voltage? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAn exponential rate of one. ","b":"B.\tOne time constant. ","c":"C.\tOne exponential period. ","d":"D.\tA time factor of one"}},{"num":80,"sample":"1B142","correct":"D","question":"What is the meaning of the term 'time constant of an RC circuit'? The time required to charge the capacitor in the circuit to: ","answers":{"a":"A.\t23.7% of the supply voltage. ","b":"B.\t36.8% of the supply voltage. ","c":"C.\t57.3% of the supply voltage. ","d":"D.\t63.2% of the supply voltage"}},{"num":81,"sample":"1B143","correct":"A","question":"What is the term for the time required for the current in an RL circuit to build up to 63.2% of the maximum value? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tOne time constant. ","b":"B.\tAn exponential period of one. ","c":"C.\tA time factor of one. ","d":"D.\tOne exponential rate"}},{"num":82,"sample":"1B144","correct":"C","question":"What is the meaning of the term 'time constant of an RL circuit'?  The time required for the: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tCurrent in the circuit to build up to 36.8% of the maximum value. ","b":"B.\tVoltage in the circuit to build up to 63.2% of the maximum value. ","c":"C.\tCurrent in the circuit to build up to 63.2% of the maximum value. ","d":"D.\tVoltage in the circuit to build up to 36.8% of the maximum value"}},{"num":83,"sample":"1B145","correct":"C","question":"After two time constants, the capacitor in an RC circuit is charged to what percentage of the supply voltage? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t36.8 %. ","b":"B.\t63.2 %. ","c":"C.\t86.5 %. ","d":"D.\t95 %"}},{"num":84,"sample":"1B146","correct":"B","question":"After two time constants, the capacitor in an RC circuit is discharged to what percentage of the starting voltage? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t86.5 %. ","b":"B.\t13.5 %. ","c":"C.\t63.2 %. ","d":"D.\t36.8 %"}},{"num":85,"sample":"1B151","correct":"D","question":"What is the time constant of a circuit having two 220-microfarad capacitors and two 1-megohm resistors all in parallel? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t22 seconds. ","b":"B.\t44 seconds. ","c":"C.\t440 seconds. ","d":"D.\t220 seconds"}},{"num":86,"sample":"1B152","correct":"B","question":"What is the time constant of a circuit having two 100-microfarad capacitors and two 470-kilohm resistors all in series? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t470 seconds. ","b":"B.\t47 seconds. ","c":"C.\t4.7 seconds. ","d":"D.\t0.47 seconds"}},{"num":87,"sample":"1B153","correct":"C","question":"What is the time constant of a circuit having a 100-microfarad capacitor and a 470-kilohm resistor in series? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t4700 seconds. ","b":"B.\t470 seconds. ","c":"C.\t47 seconds. ","d":"D.\t0.47 seconds"}},{"num":88,"sample":"1B154","correct":"A","question":"What is the time constant of a circuit having a 220-microfarad capacitor and a 1-megohm resistor in parallel? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t220 seconds. ","b":"B.\t22 seconds. ","c":"C.\t 2.2 seconds. ","d":"D.\t0.22 seconds"}},{"num":89,"sample":"1B155","correct":"B","question":"What is the time constant of a circuit having two 100-microfarad capacitors and two 470-kilohm resistors all in parallel? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t470 seconds. ","b":"B.\t47 seconds. ","c":"C.\t4.7 seconds. ","d":"D.\t0.47 seconds"}},{"num":90,"sample":"1B156","correct":"A","question":"What is the time constant of a circuit having two 220-microfarad capacitors and two 1-megohm resistors all in series? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t220 seconds. ","b":"B.\t55 seconds. ","c":"C.\t110 seconds. ","d":"D.\t440 seconds"}},{"num":91,"sample":"1B161","correct":"C","question":"What is the impedance of a network composed of a 0.1-microhenry inductor in series with a 20-ohm resistor, at 30 MHz?  Specify your answer in rectangular coordinates. ","answers":{"a":"A.\t20 -j19. ","b":"B.\t19 +j20. ","c":"C.\t20 +j19. ","d":"D.\t19 -j20"}},{"num":92,"sample":"1B162","correct":"D","question":"In rectangular coordinates, what is the impedance of a network composed of a 0.1-microhenry inductor in series with a 30-ohm resistor, at 5 MHz? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t30 -j3. ","b":"B.\t3 +j30. ","c":"C.\t3 -j30. ","d":"D.\t30 +j3"}},{"num":93,"sample":"1B163","correct":"A","question":"In rectangular coordinates, what is the impedance of a network composed of a 10-microhenry inductor in series with a 40-ohm resistor, at 500 MHz? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t40 +j31400. ","b":"B.\t40 -j31400. ","c":"C.\t31400 +j40. ","d":"D.\t31400 -j40"}},{"num":94,"sample":"1B164","correct":"B","question":"In rectangular coordinates, what is the impedance of a network composed of a 1.0-millihenry inductor in series with a 200-ohm resistor, at 30 kHz? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t200 - j188. ","b":"B.\t200 + j188. ","c":"C.\t188 + j200. ","d":"D.\t188 - j200"}},{"num":95,"sample":"1B165","correct":"C","question":"In rectangular coordinates, what is the impedance of a network composed of a 0.01-microfarad capacitor in parallel with a 300-ohm resistor, at 50 kHz? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t150 - j159. ","b":"B.\t150 + j159. ","c":"C.\t159 - j150. ","d":"D.\t159 + j150"}},{"num":96,"sample":"1B166","correct":"D","question":"In rectangular coordinates, what is the impedance of a network composed of a 0.001-microfarad capacitor in series with a 400-ohm resistor, at 500 kHz? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t318 - j400. ","b":"B.\t400 + j318. ","c":"C.\t318 + j400. ","d":"D.\t400 - j318"}},{"num":97,"sample":"1B171","correct":"D","question":"What is the impedance of a network composed of a 100-picofarad capacitor in parallel with a 4000-ohm resistor, at 500 KHz? Specify your answer in polar coordinates. ","answers":{"a":"A.\t2490 ohms, /51.5 degrees . ","b":"B.\t4000 ohms, /38.5 degrees . ","c":"C.\t5112 ohms, /-38.5 degrees. ","d":"D.\t2490 ohms, /-51.5 degrees"}},{"num":98,"sample":"1B172","correct":"B","question":"In polar coordinates, what is the impedance of a network composed of a 100-ohm-reactance inductor in series with a 100-ohm resistor? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t121 ohms, /35 degrees . ","b":"B.\t141 ohms, /45 degrees . ","c":"C.\t161 ohms, /55 degrees. ","d":"D.\t181 ohms, /65 degrees"}},{"num":99,"sample":"1B173","correct":"C","question":"In polar coordinates, what is the impedance of a network composed of a 400-ohm-reactance capacitor in series with a 300-ohm resistor? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t240 ohms, /36.9 degrees . ","b":"B.\t240 ohms, /-36.9 degrees . ","c":"C.\t500 ohms, /-53.1 degrees. ","d":"D.\t500 ohms, /53.1 degrees"}},{"num":100,"sample":"1B174","correct":"A","question":"In polar coordinates, what is the impedance of a network composed of a 300-ohm-reactance capacitor, a 600-ohm-reactance inductor, and a 400-ohm resistor, all connected in series? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t500 ohms, /37 degrees . ","b":"B.\t400 ohms, /27 degrees . ","c":"C.\t300 ohms, /17 degrees. ","d":"D.\t200 ohms, /10 degrees"}},{"num":101,"sample":"1B175","correct":"B","question":"In polar coordinates, what is the impedance of a network comprised of a 400-ohm-reactance inductor in parallel with a 300-ohm resistor? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t240 ohms, /-36.9 degrees . ","b":"B.\t240 ohms, /36.9 degrees . ","c":"C.\t500 ohms, /53.1 degrees. ","d":"D.\t500 ohms, /-53.1 degrees"}},{"num":102,"sample":"1B176","correct":"D","question":"Using the polar coordinate system, what visual representation would you get of a voltage in a sinewave circuit? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tTo show the reactance which is present. ","b":"B.\tTo graphically represent the AC and DC component. ","c":"C.\tTo display the data on an XY chart. ","d":"D.\tThe plot shows the magnitude and phase angle"}},{"num":103,"sample":"1B181","correct":"C","question":"What is the magnitude of the impedance of a series AC circuit having a resistance of 6 ohms, an inductive reactance of 17 ohms, and zero capacitive reactance? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t6.6 ohms. ","b":"B.\t11 ohms. ","c":"C.\t18 ohms. ","d":"D.\t23 ohms"}},{"num":104,"sample":"1B182","correct":"B","question":"A 1-watt, 10-volt Zener diode with the following characteristics:  Imin. = 5 mA; Imax. = 95 mA; and Z = 8 ohms, is to be used as part of a voltage regulator in a 20-V power supply. Approximately what size current-limiting resistor would be used to set its bias to the midpoint of its operating range? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t100 ohms. ","b":"B.\t200 ohms. ","c":"C.\t1 kilohms. ","d":"D.\t2 kilohms"}},{"num":105,"sample":"1B183","correct":"C","question":"Given a power supply with a no load voltage of 12 volts and a full load voltage of 10 volts, what is the percentage of voltage regulation? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t17 %. ","b":"B.\t80 %. ","c":"C.\t20 %. ","d":"D.\t83 %"}},{"num":106,"sample":"1B184","correct":"A","question":"What turns ratio does a transformer need in order to match a source impedance of 500 ohms to a load of 10 ohms? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t7.1 to 1. ","b":"B.\t14.2 to 1. ","c":"C.\t50 to 1. ","d":"D.\tNone of these"}},{"num":107,"sample":"1B185","correct":"D","question":"Given a power supply with a full load voltage of 200 volts and a regulation of 25%, what is the no load voltage? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t150 volts. ","b":"B.\t160 volts. ","c":"C.\t240 volts. ","d":"D.\t250 volts"}},{"num":108,"sample":"1B186","correct":"B","question":"What is the conductance (G) of a circuit if 6 amperes of current flows when 12 volts DC is applied? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t0.25 Siemens (mhos). ","b":"B.\t0.50 Siemens (mhos). ","c":"C.\t1.00 Siemens (mhos). ","d":"D.\t1.25 Siemens (mhos)"}},{"num":109,"sample":"1C191","correct":"A","question":"What happens to the conductivity of photoconductive material when light shines on it? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIt increases. ","b":"B.\tIt decreases. ","c":"C.\tIt stays the same. ","d":"D.\tIt becomes temperature dependent"}},{"num":110,"sample":"1C192","correct":"B","question":"What is the photoconductive effect? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe conversion of photon energy to electromotive energy. ","b":"B.\tThe increased conductivity of an illuminated semiconductor junction. ","c":"C.\tThe conversion of electromotive energy to photon energy. ","d":"D.\tThe decreased conductivity of an illuminated semiconductor junction"}},{"num":111,"sample":"1C193","correct":"D","question":"What does the photoconductive effect in crystalline solids produce a noticeable change in? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe capacitance of the solid. ","b":"B.\tThe inductance of the solid. ","c":"C.\tThe specific gravity of the solid. ","d":"D.\tThe resistance of the solid"}},{"num":112,"sample":"1C194","correct":"A","question":"What is the description of an optoisolator? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAn LED and a photosensitive device. ","b":"B.\tA P-N junction that develops an excess positive charge when exposed to light. ","c":"C.\tAn LED and a capacitor. ","d":"D.\tAn LED and a lithium battery cell"}},{"num":113,"sample":"1C195","correct":"B","question":"What happens to the conductivity of a photosensitive semiconductor junction when it is illuminated? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe junction resistance is unchanged. ","b":"B.\tThe junction resistance decreases. ","c":"C.\tThe junction resistance becomes temperature dependent. ","d":"D.\tThe junction resistance increases"}},{"num":114,"sample":"1C196","correct":"C","question":"What is the description of an optocoupler? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA resistor and a capacitor. ","b":"B.\tTwo light sources modulated onto a mirrored surface. ","c":"C.\tAn LED and a photosensitive device. ","d":"D.\tAn amplitude modulated beam encoder"}},{"num":115,"sample":"1C201","correct":"D","question":"What factors determine the capacitance of a capacitor? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tVoltage on the plates and distance between the plates. ","b":"B.\tVoltage on the plates and the dielectric constant of the material between the plates. ","c":"C.\tAmount of charge on the plates and the dielectric constant of the material between the plates. ","d":"D.\tDistance between the plates and the dielectric constant of the material between the plates"}},{"num":116,"sample":"1C202","correct":"C","question":"In Figure 3C4, if a small variable capacitor were installed in place of the dashed line, it would? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIncrease gain. ","b":"B.\tIncrease parasitic oscillations. ","c":"C.\tDecrease parasitic oscillations. ","d":"D.\tDecrease crosstalk"}},{"num":117,"sample":"1C203","correct":"B","question":"In Figure 3C4, which component (labeled 1 through 4) is used to provide a signal ground? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1. ","b":"B.\t2. ","c":"C.\t3. ","d":"D.\t4"}},{"num":118,"sample":"1C204","correct":"C","question":"In Figure 3C5, which capacitor (labeled 1 through 4) is being used as a bypass capacitor? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1 . ","b":"B.\t2 . ","c":"C.\t3. ","d":"D.\t4"}},{"num":119,"sample":"1C205","correct":"D","question":"In Figure 3C5, the 1 &mu;F capacitor is connected to a potentiometer that is used to: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIncrease gain. ","b":"B.\tNeutralize amplifier. ","c":"C.\tCouple. ","d":"D.\tAdjust tone"}},{"num":120,"sample":"1C206","correct":"A","question":"What is the purpose of a coupling capacitor? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIt blocks direct current and passes alternating current. ","b":"B.\tIt blocks alternating current and passes direct current. ","c":"C.\tIt increases the resonant frequency of the circuit. ","d":"D.\tIt decreases the resonant frequency of the circuit"}},{"num":121,"sample":"1C211","correct":"A","question":"A capacitor is sometimes placed in series with the primary of a power transformer to: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tImprove the power factor. ","b":"B.\tImprove output voltage regulation. ","c":"C.\tRectify the primary windings. ","d":"D.\tNone of these"}},{"num":122,"sample":"1C212","correct":"B","question":"A transformer used to step up its input voltage must have: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tMore turns of wire on its primary than on its secondary. ","b":"B.\tMore turns of wire on its secondary than on its primary. ","c":"C.\tEqual number of primary and secondary turns of wire. ","d":"D.\tNone of the above statements are correct"}},{"num":123,"sample":"1C213","correct":"A","question":"A transformer primary of 2250 turns connected to 120 VAC will develop what voltage across a 500-turn secondary? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t26.7 volts. ","b":"B.\t2300 volts. ","c":"C.\t1500 volts. ","d":"D.\t5.9 volts"}},{"num":124,"sample":"1C214","correct":"C","question":"What is the ratio of the output frequency to the input frequency of a single-phase full-wave rectifier? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1:1. ","b":"B.\t1:2. ","c":"C.\t2:1. ","d":"D.\tNone of these"}},{"num":125,"sample":"1C215","correct":"B","question":"A power transformer has a single primary winding and three secondary windings producing 5.0 volts, 12.6 volts, and 150 volts. Assuming similar wire sizes, which of the three secondary windings will have the highest measured DC resistance? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe 12.6 volt winding. ","b":"B.\tThe 150 volt winding. ","c":"C.\tThe 5.0 volt winding. ","d":"D.\tAll will have equal resistance values"}},{"num":126,"sample":"1C216","correct":"D","question":"A power transformer has a primary winding of 200 turns of #24 wire and a secondary winding consisting of 500 turns of the same size wire. When 20 volts are applied to the primary winding, the expected secondary voltage will be: ","answers":{"a":"A.\t500 volts. ","b":"B.\t25 volts. ","c":"C.\t10 volts. ","d":"D.\t50 volts"}},{"num":127,"sample":"1C221","correct":"D","question":"In a linear electronic voltage regulator: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe output is a ramp voltage. ","b":"B.\tThe pass transistor switches from the 'off' state to the 'on'\" state. ","c":"C.\tThe control device is switched on or off, with the duty cycle proportional to the line or load conditions. ","d":"D.\tThe conduction of a control element is varied in direct proportion to the line voltage or load current"}},{"num":128,"sample":"1C222","correct":"C","question":"A switching electronic voltage regulator: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tVaries the conduction of a control element in direct proportion to the line voltage or load current. ","b":"B.\tProvides more than one output voltage. ","c":"C.\tSwitches the control device on or off, with the duty cycle proportional to the line or load conditions. ","d":"D.\tGives a ramp voltage at its output"}},{"num":129,"sample":"1C223","correct":"A","question":"What device is usually used as a stable reference voltage in a linear voltage regulator? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tZener diode. ","b":"B.\tTunnel diode. ","c":"C.\tSCR. ","d":"D.\tVaractor diode"}},{"num":130,"sample":"1C224","correct":"D","question":"In a regulated power supply, what type of component will most likely be used to establish a reference voltage? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tTunnel Diode. ","b":"B.\tBattery. ","c":"C.\tPass Transistor. ","d":"D.\tZener Diode"}},{"num":131,"sample":"1C225","correct":"C","question":"A three-terminal regulator: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tSupplies three voltages with variable current. ","b":"B.\tSupplies three voltages at a constant current. ","c":"C.\tContains a voltage reference, error amplifier, sensing resistors and transistors, and a pass element. ","d":"D.\tContains three error amplifiers and sensing transistors"}},{"num":132,"sample":"1C226","correct":"B","question":"What is the range of voltage ratings available in Zener diodes? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1.2 volts to 7 volts. ","b":"B.\t2.4 volts to 200 volts and above. ","c":"C.\t3 volts to 2000 volts. ","d":"D.\t1.2 volts to 5.6 volts"}},{"num":133,"sample":"1C231","correct":"C","question":"How might two similar SCRs be connected to safely distribute the power load of a circuit? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIn series. ","b":"B.\tIn parallel, same polarity. ","c":"C.\tIn parallel, reverse polarity. ","d":"D.\tIn a combination series and parallel configuration"}},{"num":134,"sample":"1C232","correct":"A","question":"What are the three terminals of an SCR? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAnode, cathode, and gate. ","b":"B.\tGate, source, and sink. ","c":"C.\tBase, collector, and emitter. ","d":"D.\tGate, base 1, and base 2"}},{"num":135,"sample":"1C233","correct":"D","question":"Which of the following devices acts as two SCRs connected back to back, but facing in opposite directions and sharing a common gate? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tJFET. ","b":"B.\tDual-gate MOSFET. ","c":"C.\tDIAC. ","d":"D.\tTRIAC"}},{"num":136,"sample":"1C234","correct":"A","question":"What is the transistor called that is fabricated as two complementary SCRs in parallel with a common gate terminal? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tTRIAC. ","b":"B.\tBilateral SCR. ","c":"C.\tUnijunction transistor. ","d":"D.\tField effect transistor"}},{"num":137,"sample":"1C235","correct":"D","question":"What are the three terminals of a TRIAC? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tEmitter, base 1, and base 2. ","b":"B.\tBase, emitter, and collector. ","c":"C.\tGate, source, and sink. ","d":"D.\tGate, anode 1, and anode 2"}},{"num":138,"sample":"1C236","correct":"B","question":"What circuit might contain a SCR? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tFilament circuit of a tube radio receiver. ","b":"B.\tA light-dimming circuit. ","c":"C.\tShunt across a transformer primary. ","d":"D.\tBypass capacitor circuit to ground"}},{"num":139,"sample":"1C241","correct":"B","question":"What is one common use for PIN diodes? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tConstant current source. ","b":"B.\tRF switch. ","c":"C.\tConstant voltage source. ","d":"D.\tRF rectifier"}},{"num":140,"sample":"1C242","correct":"D","question":"What is a common use of a hot-carrier diode? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBalanced inputs in SSB generation. ","b":"B.\tVariable capacitance in an automatic frequency control circuit. ","c":"C.\tConstant voltage reference in a power supply. ","d":"D.\tVHF and UHF mixers and detectors"}},{"num":141,"sample":"1C243","correct":"A","question":"Structurally, what are the two main categories of semiconductor diodes? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tJunction and point contact. ","b":"B.\tElectrolytic and junction. ","c":"C.\tElectrolytic and point contact. ","d":"D.\tVacuum and point contact"}},{"num":142,"sample":"1C244","correct":"C","question":"What special type of diode is capable of both amplification and oscillation? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tZener diodes. ","b":"B.\tPoint contact diodes. ","c":"C.\tTunnel diodes. ","d":"D.\tJunction diodes"}},{"num":143,"sample":"1C245","correct":"B","question":"What type of semiconductor diode varies its internal capacitance as the voltage applied to its terminals varies? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tTunnel diode. ","b":"B.\tVaractor diode. ","c":"C.\tSilicon-controlled rectifier. ","d":"D.\tZener diode"}},{"num":144,"sample":"1C246","correct":"C","question":"What is the principal characteristic of a tunnel diode? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tHigh forward resistance. ","b":"B.\tVery high PIV(peak inverse voltage). ","c":"C.\tNegative resistance region. ","d":"D.\tHigh forward current rating"}},{"num":145,"sample":"1C251","correct":"D","question":"What is the meaning of the term 'alpha' with regard to bipolar transistors?  The change of: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tCollector current with respect to base current. ","b":"B.\tBase current with respect to collector current. ","c":"C.\tCollector current with respect to gate current. ","d":"D.\tCollector current with respect to emitter current"}},{"num":146,"sample":"1C252","correct":"B","question":"What are the three terminals of a bipolar transistor? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tCathode, plate and grid. ","b":"B.\tBase, collector and emitter. ","c":"C.\tGate, source and sink. ","d":"D.\tInput, output and ground"}},{"num":147,"sample":"1C253","correct":"C","question":"What is the meaning of the term 'beta' with regard to bipolar transistors?  The change of: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBase current with respect to emitter current. ","b":"B.\tCollector current with respect to emitter current. ","c":"C.\tCollector current with respect to base current. ","d":"D.\tBase current with respect to gate current"}},{"num":148,"sample":"1C254","correct":"A","question":"What are the elements of a unijunction transistor? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBase 1, base 2, and emitter. ","b":"B.\tGate, cathode, and anode. ","c":"C.\tGate, base 1, and base 2. ","d":"D.\tGate, source, and sink"}},{"num":149,"sample":"1C255","correct":"B","question":"The beta cutoff frequency of a bipolar transistor is the frequency at which: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBase current gain has increased to 0.707 of maximum. ","b":"B.\tEmitter current gain has decreased to 0.707 of maximum. ","c":"C.\tCollector current gain has decreased to 0.707. ","d":"D.\tGate current gain has decreased to 0.707"}},{"num":150,"sample":"1C256","correct":"A","question":"What does it mean for a transistor to be fully saturated? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe collector current is at its maximum value. ","b":"B.\tThe collector current is at its minimum value. ","c":"C.\tThe transistor's Alpha is at its maximum value. ","d":"D.\tThe transistor's Beta is at its maximum value"}},{"num":151,"sample":"1C261","correct":"B","question":"A common base amplifier has: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tMore current gain than common emitter or common collector. ","b":"B.\tMore voltage gain than common emitter or common collector. ","c":"C.\tMore power gain than common emitter or common collector. ","d":"D.\tHighest input impedance of the three amplifier configurations"}},{"num":152,"sample":"1C262","correct":"C","question":"What does it mean for a transistor to be cut off? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThere is no base current. ","b":"B.\tThe transistor is at its Class A operating point. ","c":"C.\tThere is no current between emitter and collector. ","d":"D.\tThere is maximum current between emitter and collector"}},{"num":153,"sample":"1C263","correct":"D","question":"An emitter-follower amplifier has: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tMore voltage gain than common emitter or common base. ","b":"B.\tMore power gain than common emitter or common base. ","c":"C.\tLowest input impedance of the three amplifier configurations. ","d":"D.\tMore current gain than common emitter or common base"}},{"num":154,"sample":"1C264","correct":"A","question":"What conditions exists when a transistor is operating in saturation? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe base-emitter junction and collector-base junction are both forward biased. ","b":"B.\tThe base-emitter junction and collector-base junction are both reverse biased. ","c":"C.\tThe base-emitter junction is reverse biased and the collector-base junction is forward biased. ","d":"D.\tThe base-emitter junction is forward biased and the collector-base junction is reverse biased"}},{"num":155,"sample":"1C265","correct":"C","question":"For current to flow in an NPN silicon transistor's emitter-collector junction, the base must be: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAt least 0.4 volts positive with respect to the emitter. ","b":"B.\tAt a negative voltage with respect to the emitter. ","c":"C.\tAt least 0.7 volts positive with respect to the emitter. ","d":"D.\tAt least 0.7 volts negative with respect to the emitter"}},{"num":156,"sample":"1C266","correct":"D","question":"When an NPN transistor is operating as a Class A amplifier, the base-emitter junction: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAnd collector-base junction are both forward biased. ","b":"B.\tAnd collector-base junction are both reverse biased. ","c":"C.\tIs reverse biased and the collector-base junction is forward biased. ","d":"D.\tIs forward biased and the collector-base junction is reverse biased"}},{"num":157,"sample":"1C271","correct":"B","question":"What type of bias is required for an LED to produce luminescence? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tReverse bias. ","b":"B.\tForward bias. ","c":"C.\tLogic 0 (Lo) bias. ","d":"D.\tLogic 1 (Hi) bias"}},{"num":158,"sample":"1C272","correct":"D","question":"What determines the visible color radiated by an LED junction? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe color of a lens in an eyepiece. ","b":"B.\tThe amount of voltage across the device. ","c":"C.\tThe amount of current through the device. ","d":"D.\tThe materials used to construct the device"}},{"num":159,"sample":"1C273","correct":"A","question":"What is the approximate operating current of a light-emitting diode? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t20 mA. ","b":"B.\t5 mA. ","c":"C.\t10 mA. ","d":"D.\t400 mA"}},{"num":160,"sample":"1C274","correct":"D","question":"What would be the maximum current to safely illuminate a LED? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1 amp. ","b":"B.\t1 microamp. ","c":"C.\t500 milliamps. ","d":"D.\t20 mA"}},{"num":161,"sample":"1C275","correct":"A","question":"An LED facing a photodiode in a light-tight enclosure is commonly known as a/an: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tOptoisolator. ","b":"B.\tSeven segment LED. ","c":"C.\tOptointerrupter. ","d":"D.\tInfra-red (IR) detector"}},{"num":162,"sample":"1C276","correct":"C","question":"What circuit component must be connected in series to protect an LED? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBypass capacitor to ground. ","b":"B.\tElectrolytic capacitor. ","c":"C.\tSeries resistor. ","d":"D.\tShunt coil in series"}},{"num":163,"sample":"1C281","correct":"C","question":"What describes a diode junction that is forward biased? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIt is a high impedance. ","b":"B.\tIt conducts very little current. ","c":"C.\tIt is a low impedance. ","d":"D.\tIt is an open circuit"}},{"num":164,"sample":"1C282","correct":"B","question":"Why are special precautions necessary in handling FET and CMOS devices? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThey have fragile leads that may break off. ","b":"B.\tThey are susceptible to damage from static charges. ","c":"C.\tThey have micro-welded semiconductor junctions that are susceptible to breakage. ","d":"D.\tThey are light sensitive"}},{"num":165,"sample":"1C283","correct":"C","question":"What do the initials CMOS stand for? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tCommon mode oscillating system. ","b":"B.\tComplementary mica-oxide silicon. ","c":"C.\tComplementary metal-oxide semiconductor. ","d":"D.\tComplementary metal-oxide substrate"}},{"num":166,"sample":"1C284","correct":"A","question":"What is the piezoelectric effect? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tMechanical vibration of a crystal by the application of a voltage. ","b":"B.\tMechanical deformation of a crystal by the application of a magnetic field. ","c":"C.\tThe generation of electrical energy by the application of light. ","d":"D.\tReversed conduction states when a P-N junction is exposed to light"}},{"num":167,"sample":"1C285","correct":"D","question":"An electrical relay is a: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tCurrent limiting device. ","b":"B.\tDevice used for supplying 3 or more voltages to a circuit. ","c":"C.\tComponent used mainly with HF audio amplifiers. ","d":"D.\tRemotely controlled switching device"}},{"num":168,"sample":"1C286","correct":"B","question":"In which oscillator circuit would you find a quartz crystal? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tHartley. ","b":"B.\tPierce ","c":"C.\tColpitts. ","d":"D.\tAll of the above"}},{"num":169,"sample":"1D291","correct":"A","question":"What is the approximate magnitude of the impedance of a parallel R-L-C circuit at resonance? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tApproximately equal to the circuit resistance. ","b":"B.\tApproximately equal to XL. ","c":"C.\tLow, as compared to the circuit resistance. ","d":"D.\tApproximately equal to XC"}},{"num":170,"sample":"1D292","correct":"B","question":"What is the approximate magnitude of the impedance of a series R-L-C circuit at resonance? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tHigh, as compared to the circuit resistance. ","b":"B.\tApproximately equal to the circuit resistance. ","c":"C.\tApproximately equal to XL. ","d":"D.\tApproximately equal to XC"}},{"num":171,"sample":"1D293","correct":"D","question":"How could voltage be greater across reactances in series than the applied voltage? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tResistance. ","b":"B.\tConductance. ","c":"C.\tCapacitance. ","d":"D.\tResonance"}},{"num":172,"sample":"1D294","correct":"A","question":"What is the characteristic of the current flow in a series R-L-C circuit at resonance? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tMaximum. ","b":"B.\tMinimum. ","c":"C.\tDC. ","d":"D.\tZero"}},{"num":173,"sample":"1D295","correct":"B","question":"What is the characteristic of the current flow within the parallel elements in a parallel R-L-C circuit at resonance? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tMinimum. ","b":"B.\tMaximum. ","c":"C.\tDC. ","d":"D.\tZero"}},{"num":174,"sample":"1D296","correct":"C","question":"What is the relationship between current through a resonant circuit and the voltage across the circuit? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe current and voltage are 180 degrees out of phase. ","b":"B.\tThe current leads the voltage by 90 degrees. ","c":"C.\tThe voltage and current are in phase. ","d":"D.\tThe voltage leads the current by 90 degrees"}},{"num":175,"sample":"1D301","correct":"D","question":"What is the main advantage of using an op-amp audio filter over a passive LC audio filter? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tOp-amps are largely immune to vibration and temperature change. ","b":"B.\tMost LC filter manufacturers have retooled to make op-amp filters. ","c":"C.\tOp-amps are readily available in a wide variety of operational voltages and frequency ranges. ","d":"D.\tOp-amps exhibit gain rather than insertion loss"}},{"num":176,"sample":"1D302","correct":"C","question":"What are the characteristics of an inverting operational amplifier (op-amp) circuit? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIt has input and output signals in phase. ","b":"B.\tInput and output signals are 90 degrees out of phase. ","c":"C.\tIt has input and output signals 180 degrees out of phase. ","d":"D.\tInput impedance is low while the output impedance is high"}},{"num":177,"sample":"1D303","correct":"B","question":"Gain of a closed-loop op-amp circuit is determined by? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe maximum operating frequency divided by the square root of the load impedance. ","b":"B.\tThe op-amp's external feedback network. ","c":"C.\tSupply voltage and slew rate. ","d":"D.\tThe op-amp's internal feedback network"}},{"num":178,"sample":"1D304","correct":"C","question":"Where is the external feedback network connected to control the gain of a closed-loop op-amp circuit? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBetween the differential inputs. ","b":"B.\tFrom output to the non-inverting input. ","c":"C.\tFrom output to the inverting input. ","d":"D.\tBetween the output and the differential inputs"}},{"num":179,"sample":"1D305","correct":"D","question":"Which of the following op-amp circuits is operated open-loop? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tNon-inverting amp. ","b":"B.\tInverting amp. ","c":"C.\tActive filter. ","d":"D.\tComparator"}},{"num":180,"sample":"1D306","correct":"A","question":"In the op-amp oscillator circuit shown in Figure 3D6, what would be the most noticeable effect if the capacitance of C were suddenly doubled? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tFrequency would be lower. ","b":"B.\tFrequency would be higher. ","c":"C.\tThere would be no change. The inputs are reversed, therefore the circuit cannot function. ","d":"D.\tNone of the above"}},{"num":181,"sample":"1D311","correct":"A","question":"What frequency synthesizer circuit uses a phase comparator, look-up table, digital-to-analog converter, and a low-pass antialias filter? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA direct digital synthesizer. ","b":"B.\tPhase-locked-loop synthesizer. ","c":"C.\tA diode-switching matrix synthesizer. ","d":"D.\tA hybrid synthesizer"}},{"num":182,"sample":"1D312","correct":"B","question":"A circuit that compares the output of a voltage-controlled oscillator (VCO) to a frequency standard and produces an error voltage that is then used to adjust the capacitance of a varactor diode used to control frequency in that same VCO is called what? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tDoubly balanced mixer. ","b":"B.\tPhase-locked loop. ","c":"C.\tDifferential voltage amplifier. ","d":"D.\tVariable frequency oscillator"}},{"num":183,"sample":"1D313","correct":"A","question":"RF input to a mixer is 200 MHz and the local oscillator frequency is 150 MHz. What output would you expect to see at the IF output prior to any filtering? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t50, 150, 200 and 350 MHz. ","b":"B.\t50 MHz. ","c":"C.\t350 MHz. ","d":"D.\t50 and 350 MHz"}},{"num":184,"sample":"1D314","correct":"C","question":"What spectral impurity components might be generated by a phase-locked-loop synthesizer? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tSpurs at discrete frequencies. ","b":"B.\tRandom spurs which gradually drift up in frequency. ","c":"C.\tBroadband noise. ","d":"D.\tDigital conversion noise"}},{"num":185,"sample":"1D315","correct":"B","question":"In a direct digital synthesizer, what are the unwanted components on its output? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBroadband noise. ","b":"B.\tSpurs at discrete frequencies. ","c":"C.\tDigital conversion noise. ","d":"D.\tNyquist limit noise pulses"}},{"num":186,"sample":"1D316","correct":"D","question":"What is the definition of a phase-locked loop (PLL) circuit? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA servo loop consisting of a ratio detector, reactance modulator, and voltage-controlled oscillator. ","b":"B.\tA circuit also known as a monostable multivibrator. ","c":"C.\tA circuit consisting of a precision push-pull amplifier with a differential input. ","d":"D.\tA servo loop consisting of a phase detector, a low-pass filter and voltage-controlled oscillator"}},{"num":187,"sample":"1D321","correct":"D","question":"Given the combined DC input voltages, what would the output voltage be in the circuit shown in Figure 3D7? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t150 mV. ","b":"B.\t5.5 V. ","c":"C.\t-15 mv. ","d":"D.\t-5.5 V"}},{"num":188,"sample":"1D322","correct":"C","question":"Which lamps would be lit in the circuit shown in Figure 3D8? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t2, 3, 4, 5 and 6. ","b":"B.\t5, 6, 8 and 9. ","c":"C.\t2, 3, 4, 7 and 8. ","d":"D.\t1, 3, 5, 7 and 8"}},{"num":189,"sample":"1D323","correct":"A","question":"What will occur if an amplifier input signal coupling capacitor fails open? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tNo amplification will occur, with DC within the circuit measuring normal. ","b":"B.\tImproper biasing will occur within the amplifier stage. ","c":"C.\tOscillation and thermal runaway may occur. ","d":"D.\tAn AC hum will appear on the circuit output"}},{"num":190,"sample":"1D324","correct":"D","question":"In Figure 3D9, determine if there is a problem with this regulated power supply and identify the problem. ","answers":{"a":"A.\tR1 value is too low which would cause excessive base current and instantly destroy TR 1. ","b":"B.\tD1 and D2 are reversed. The power supply simply would not function. ","c":"C.\tTR1 is shown as an NPN and must be changed to a PNP. ","d":"D.\tThere is no problem with the circuit"}},{"num":191,"sample":"1D325","correct":"C","question":"In Figure 3D10 with a square wave input what would be the output? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1. ","b":"B.\t2. ","c":"C.\t3. ","d":"D.\t4"}},{"num":192,"sample":"1D326","correct":"B","question":"With a pure AC signal input to the circuit shown in Figure 3D11, what output wave form would you expect to see on an oscilloscope display? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1. ","b":"B.\t2. ","c":"C.\t3. ","d":"D.\t4"}},{"num":193,"sample":"1E331","correct":"C","question":"What is the voltage range considered to be valid logic low input in a TTL device operating at 5 volts? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t2.0 to 5.5 volts. ","b":"B.\t-2.0 to -5.5 volts. ","c":"C.\tZero to 0.8 volts. ","d":"D.\t5.2 to 34.8 volts"}},{"num":194,"sample":"1E332","correct":"A","question":"What is the voltage range considered to be a valid logic high input in a TTL device operating at 5.0 volts? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t2.0 to 5.5 volts. ","b":"B.\t1.5 to 3.0 volts. ","c":"C.\t1.0 to 1.5 volts. ","d":"D.\t5.2 to 34.8 volts"}},{"num":195,"sample":"1E333","correct":"D","question":"What is the common power supply voltage for TTL series integrated circuits? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t12 volts. ","b":"B.\t13.6 volts. ","c":"C.\t1 volt. ","d":"D.\t5 volts"}},{"num":196,"sample":"1E334","correct":"A","question":"TTL inputs left open develop what logic state? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA high-logic state. ","b":"B.\tA low-logic state. ","c":"C.\tOpen inputs on a TTL device are ignored. ","d":"D.\tRandom high- and low-logic states"}},{"num":197,"sample":"1E335","correct":"D","question":"Which of the following instruments would be best for checking a TTL logic circuit? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tVOM. ","b":"B.\tDMM. ","c":"C.\tContinuity tester. ","d":"D.\tLogic probe"}},{"num":198,"sample":"1E336","correct":"B","question":"What do the initials TTL stand for? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tResistor-transistor logic. ","b":"B.\tTransistor-transistor logic. ","c":"C.\tDiode-transistor logic. ","d":"D.\tEmitter-coupled logic"}},{"num":199,"sample":"1E341","correct":"B","question":"What is a characteristic of an AND gate? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tProduces a logic '0' at its output only if all inputs are logic '1'. ","b":"B.\tProduces a logic '1' at its output only if all inputs are logic '1'. ","c":"C.\tProduces a logic '1' at its output if only one input is a logic '1'. ","d":"D.\tProduces a logic '1' at its output if all inputs are logic '0'"}},{"num":200,"sample":"1E342","correct":"D","question":"What is a characteristic of a NAND gate? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tProduces a logic '0' at its output only when all inputs are logic '0'. ","b":"B.\tProduces a logic '1' at its output only when all inputs are logic '1'. ","c":"C.\tProduces a logic '0' at its output if some but not all of its inputs are logic '1'. ","d":"D.\tProduces a logic '0' at its output only when all inputs are logic '1'"}},{"num":201,"sample":"1E343","correct":"A","question":"What is a characteristic of an OR gate? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tProduces a logic '1' at its output if any input is logic '1'. ","b":"B.\tProduces a logic '0' at its output if any input is logic '1'. ","c":"C.\tProduces a logic '0' at its output if all inputs are logic '1'. ","d":"D.\tProduces a logic '1' at its output if all inputs are logic '0'"}},{"num":202,"sample":"1E344","correct":"C","question":"What is a characteristic of a NOR gate? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tProduces a logic '0' at its output only if all inputs are logic '0'. ","b":"B.\tProduces a logic '1' at its output only if all inputs are logic '1'. ","c":"C.\tProduces a logic '0' at its output if any or all inputs are logic '1'. ","d":"D.\tProduces a logic '1' at its output if some but not all of its inputs are logic '1'"}},{"num":203,"sample":"1E345","correct":"B","question":"What is a characteristic of a NOT gate? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tDoes not allow data transmission when its input is high. ","b":"B.\tProduces a logic '0' at its output when the input is logic '1' and vice versa. ","c":"C.\tAllows data transmission only when its input is high. ","d":"D.\tProduces a logic \"1\" at its output when the input is logic \"1\" and vice versa"}},{"num":204,"sample":"1E346","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following logic gates will provide an active high out when both inputs are active high? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tNAND. ","b":"B.\tNOR. ","c":"C.\tAND. ","d":"D.\tXOR"}},{"num":205,"sample":"1E351","correct":"D","question":"In a negative-logic circuit, what level is used to represent a logic 0? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tLow level. ","b":"B.\tPositive-transition level. ","c":"C.\tNegative-transition level. ","d":"D.\tHigh level"}},{"num":206,"sample":"1E352","correct":"B","question":"For the logic input levels shown in Figure 3E12, what are the logic levels of test points A, B and C in this circuit? (Assume positive logic.) ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA is high, B is low and C is low. ","b":"B.\tA is low, B is high and C is high. ","c":"C.\tA is high, B is high and C is low. ","d":"D.\tA is low, B is high and C is low"}},{"num":207,"sample":"1E353","correct":"C","question":"For the logic input levels given in Figure 3E13, what are the logic levels of test points A, B and C in this circuit? (Assume positive logic.) ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA is low, B is low and C is high. ","b":"B.\tA is low, B is high and C is low. ","c":"C.\tA is high, B is high and C is high. ","d":"D.\tA is high, B is low and C is low"}},{"num":208,"sample":"1E354","correct":"A","question":"In a positive-logic circuit, what level is used to represent a logic 1? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tHigh level . ","b":"B.\tLow level . ","c":"C.\tPositive-transition level. ","d":"D.\tNegative-transition level"}},{"num":209,"sample":"1E355","correct":"A","question":"Given the input levels shown in Figure 3E14 and assuming positive logic devices, what would the output be? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA is low, B is high and C is high. ","b":"B.\tA is high, B is high and C is low.  ","c":"C.\tA is low, B is low and C is high.  ","d":"D.\tNone of the above are correct"}},{"num":210,"sample":"1E356","correct":"A","question":"What is a truth table? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA list of input combinations and their corresponding outputs that characterizes a digital device's function. ","b":"B.\tA table of logic symbols that indicate the high logic states of an op-amp. ","c":"C.\tA diagram showing logic states when the digital device's output is true. ","d":"D.\tA table of logic symbols that indicates the low logic states of an op-amp"}},{"num":211,"sample":"1E361","correct":"B","question":"A flip-flop circuit is a binary logic element with how many stable states? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1. ","b":"B.\t2. ","c":"C.\t4. ","d":"D.\t8"}},{"num":212,"sample":"1E362","correct":"C","question":"What is a flip-flop circuit?  A binary sequential logic element with ___stable states. ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1. ","b":"B.\t4. ","c":"C.\t2. ","d":"D.\t8"}},{"num":213,"sample":"1E363","correct":"D","question":"How many flip-flops are required to divide a signal frequency by 4? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1. ","b":"B.\t4. ","c":"C.\t8. ","d":"D.\t2"}},{"num":214,"sample":"1E364","correct":"A","question":"How many bits of information can be stored in a single flip-flop circuit? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1. ","b":"B.\t2. ","c":"C.\t3. ","d":"D.\t4"}},{"num":215,"sample":"1E365","correct":"C","question":"How many R-S flip-flops would be required to construct an 8 bit storage register? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t2. ","b":"B.\t4. ","c":"C.\t8. ","d":"D.\t16"}},{"num":216,"sample":"1E366","correct":"D","question":"An R-S flip-flop is capable of doing all of the following except: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAccept data input into R-S inputs with CLK initiated. ","b":"B.\tAccept data input into PRE and CLR inputs without CLK being initiated. ","c":"C.\tRefuse to accept synchronous data if asynchronous data is being input at same time. ","d":"D.\tOperate in toggle mode with R-S inputs held constant and CLK initiated"}},{"num":217,"sample":"1E371","correct":"B","question":"The frequency of an AC signal can be divided electronically by what type of digital circuit? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tFree-running multivibrator. ","b":"B.\tBistable multivibrator. ","c":"C.\tOR gate. ","d":"D.\tAstable multivibrator"}},{"num":218,"sample":"1E372","correct":"D","question":"What is an astable multivibrator? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA circuit that alternates between two stable states. ","b":"B.\tA circuit that alternates between a stable state and an unstable state. ","c":"C.\tA circuit set to block either a 0 pulse or a 1 pulse and pass the other. ","d":"D.\tA circuit that alternates between two unstable states"}},{"num":219,"sample":"1E373","correct":"A","question":"What is a monostable multivibrator? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA circuit that can be switched momentarily to the opposite binary state and then returns after a set time to its original state. ","b":"B.\tA 'clock' circuit that produces a continuous square wave oscillating between 1 and 0. ","c":"C.\tA circuit designed to store one bit of data in either the 0 or the 1 configuration. ","d":"D.\tA circuit that maintains a constant output voltage, regardless of variations in the input voltage"}},{"num":220,"sample":"1E374","correct":"D","question":"What is a bistable multivibrator circuit commonly named? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAND gate. ","b":"B.\tOR gate. ","c":"C.\tClock. ","d":"D.\tFlip-flop"}},{"num":221,"sample":"1E375","correct":"A","question":"What is a bistable multivibrator circuit? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tFlip-flop. ","b":"B.\tAND gate. ","c":"C.\tOR gate. ","d":"D.\tClock"}},{"num":222,"sample":"1E376","correct":"C","question":"What wave form would appear on the voltage outputs at the collectors of an astable, multivibrator, common-emitter stage? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tSine wave. ","b":"B.\tSawtooth wave. ","c":"C.\tSquare wave. ","d":"D.\tHalf-wave pulses"}},{"num":223,"sample":"1E381","correct":"C","question":"What is the name of the semiconductor memory IC whose digital data can be written or read, and whose memory word address can be accessed randomly? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tROM - Read-Only Memory. ","b":"B.\tPROM - Programmable Read-Only Memory. ","c":"C.\tRAM - Random-Access Memory. ","d":"D.\tEPROM - Electrically Programmable Read-Only Memory"}},{"num":224,"sample":"1E382","correct":"B","question":"What is the name of the semiconductor IC that has a fixed pattern of digital data stored in its memory matrix? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tRAM - Random-Access Memory. ","b":"B.\tROM - Read-Only Memory. ","c":"C.\tRegister. ","d":"D.\tLatch"}},{"num":225,"sample":"1E383","correct":"C","question":"What does the term 'IO' mean within a microprocessor system? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIntegrated oscillator. ","b":"B.\tInteger operation. ","c":"C.\tInput-output. ","d":"D.\tInternal operation"}},{"num":226,"sample":"1E384","correct":"A","question":"What is the name for a microprocessor's sequence of commands and instructions? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tProgram. ","b":"B.\tSequence. ","c":"C.\tData string. ","d":"D.\tData execution"}},{"num":227,"sample":"1E385","correct":"D","question":"How many individual memory cells would be contained in a memory IC that has 4 data bus input/output pins and 4 address pins for connection to the address bus? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t8. ","b":"B.\t16. ","c":"C.\t32. ","d":"D.\t64"}},{"num":228,"sample":"1E386","correct":"B","question":"What is the name of the random-accessed semiconductor memory IC that must be refreshed periodically to maintain reliable data storage in its memory matrix? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tROM - Read-Only Memory. ","b":"B.\tDRAM - Dynamic Random-Access Memory. ","c":"C.\tPROM - Programmable Read-Only Memory. ","d":"D.\tPRAM - Programmable Random-Access Memory"}},{"num":229,"sample":"1E391","correct":"A","question":"In a microprocessor-controlled two-way radio, a 'watchdog' timer: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tVerifies that the microprocessor is executing the program. ","b":"B.\tAssures that the transmission is exactly on frequency. ","c":"C.\tPrevents the transmitter from exceeding allowed power out. ","d":"D.\tConnects to the system RADAR presentation"}},{"num":230,"sample":"1E392","correct":"B","question":"What does the term 'DAC' refer to in a microprocessor circuit? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tDynamic access controller. ","b":"B.\tDigital to analog converter. ","c":"C.\tDigital access counter. ","d":"D.\tDial analog control"}},{"num":231,"sample":"1E393","correct":"D","question":"Which of the following is not part of a MCU processor? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tRAM. ","b":"B.\tROM. ","c":"C.\tI/O. ","d":"D.\tVoltage Regulator"}},{"num":232,"sample":"1E394","correct":"A","question":"What portion of a microprocessor circuit is the pulse generator? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tClock. ","b":"B.\tRAM. ","c":"C.\tROM. ","d":"D.\tPLL"}},{"num":233,"sample":"1E395","correct":"B","question":"In a microprocessor, what is the meaning of the term 'ALU'? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAutomatic lock/unlock. ","b":"B.\tArithmetical logic unit. ","c":"C.\tAuto latch undo. ","d":"D.\tAnswer local unit"}},{"num":234,"sample":"1E396","correct":"C","question":"What circuit interconnects the microprocessor with the memory and input/output system? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tControl logic bus. ","b":"B.\tPLL line. ","c":"C.\tData bus line. ","d":"D.\tDirectional coupler"}},{"num":235,"sample":"1E401","correct":"D","question":"What is the purpose of a prescaler circuit? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tConverts the output of a JK flip-flop to that of an RS flip-flop. ","b":"B.\tMultiplies an HF signal so a low-frequency counter can display the operating frequency. ","c":"C.\tPrevents oscillation in a low frequency counter circuit. ","d":"D.\tDivides an HF signal so that a low-frequency counter can display the operating frequency"}},{"num":236,"sample":"1E402","correct":"C","question":"What does the term 'BCD' mean? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBinaural coded digit. ","b":"B.\tBit count decimal. ","c":"C.\tBinary coded decimal. ","d":"D.\tBroad course digit"}},{"num":237,"sample":"1E403","correct":"B","question":"What is the function of a decade counter digital IC? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tDecode a decimal number for display on a seven-segment LED display. ","b":"B.\tProduce one output pulse for every ten input pulses. ","c":"C.\tProduce ten output pulses for every input pulse. ","d":"D.\tAdd two decimal numbers"}},{"num":238,"sample":"1E404","correct":"C","question":"What integrated circuit device converts an analog signal to a digital signal? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tDAC. ","b":"B.\tDCC. ","c":"C.\tADC. ","d":"D.\tCDC"}},{"num":239,"sample":"1E405","correct":"D","question":"What integrated circuit device converts digital signals to analog signals? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tADC. ","b":"B.\tDCC. ","c":"C.\tCDC. ","d":"D.\tDAC"}},{"num":240,"sample":"1E406","correct":"A","question":"In binary numbers, how would you note the quantity TWO? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t0010. ","b":"B.\t0002. ","c":"C.\t2000. ","d":"D.\t0020"}},{"num":241,"sample":"1F411","correct":"A","question":"What is the limiting condition for sensitivity in a communications receiver? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe noise floor of the receiver. ","b":"B.\tThe power supply output ripple. ","c":"C.\tThe two-tone intermodulation distortion. ","d":"D.\tThe input impedance to the detector"}},{"num":242,"sample":"1F412","correct":"B","question":"What is the definition of the term 'receiver desensitizing'? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA burst of noise when the squelch is set too low. ","b":"B.\tA reduction in receiver sensitivity because of a strong signal on a nearby frequency. ","c":"C.\tA burst of noise when the squelch is set too high. ","d":"D.\tA reduction in receiver sensitivity when the AF gain control is turned down"}},{"num":243,"sample":"1F413","correct":"A","question":"What is the term used to refer to a reduction in receiver sensitivity caused by unwanted high-level adjacent channel signals? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tDesensitizing. ","b":"B.\tIntermodulation distortion. ","c":"C.\tQuieting. ","d":"D.\tOverloading"}},{"num":244,"sample":"1F414","correct":"C","question":"What is meant by the term noise figure of a communications receiver? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe level of noise entering the receiver from the antenna. ","b":"B.\tThe relative strength of a received signal 3 kHz removed from the carrier frequency. ","c":"C.\tThe level of noise generated in the front end and succeeding stages of a receiver. ","d":"D.\tThe ability of a receiver to reject unwanted signals at frequencies close to the desired one"}},{"num":245,"sample":"1F415","correct":"B","question":"Which stage of a receiver primarily establishes its noise figure? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe audio stage. ","b":"B.\tThe RF stage. ","c":"C.\tThe IF strip. ","d":"D.\tThe local oscillator"}},{"num":246,"sample":"1F416","correct":"D","question":"What is the term for the ratio between the largest tolerable receiver input signal and the minimum discernible signal? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIntermodulation distortion. ","b":"B.\tNoise floor. ","c":"C.\tNoise figure. ","d":"D.\tDynamic range"}},{"num":247,"sample":"1F421","correct":"D","question":"How can selectivity be achieved in the front-end circuitry of a communications receiver? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBy using an audio filter. ","b":"B.\tBy using an additional RF amplifier stage. ","c":"C.\tBy using an additional IF amplifier stage. ","d":"D.\tBy using a preselector"}},{"num":248,"sample":"1F422","correct":"C","question":"What is the primary purpose of an RF amplifier in a receiver? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tTo provide most of the receiver gain. ","b":"B.\tTo vary the receiver image rejection by utilizing the AGC. ","c":"C.\tTo improve the receiver's noise figure. ","d":"D.\tTo develop the AGC voltage"}},{"num":249,"sample":"1F423","correct":"A","question":"How much gain should be used in the RF amplifier stage of a receiver? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tSufficient gain to allow weak signals to overcome noise generated in the first mixer stage. ","b":"B.\tAs much gain as possible short of self oscillation. ","c":"C.\tSufficient gain to keep weak signals below the noise of the first mixer stage. ","d":"D.\tIt depends on the amplification factor of the first IF stage"}},{"num":250,"sample":"1F424","correct":"D","question":"Too much gain in a VHF receiver front end could result in this: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tLocal signals become weaker. ","b":"B.\tDifficult to match receiver impedances. ","c":"C.\tDramatic increase in receiver current. ","d":"D.\tSusceptibility of intermodulation interference from nearby transmitters"}},{"num":251,"sample":"1F425","correct":"C","question":"What is the advantage of a GaAsFET preamplifier in a modern VHF radio receiver? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIncreased selectivity and flat gain. ","b":"B.\tLow gain but high selectivity. ","c":"C.\tHigh gain and low noise floor. ","d":"D.\tHigh gain with high noise floor"}},{"num":252,"sample":"1F426","correct":"B","question":"In what stage of a VHF receiver would a low noise amplifier be most advantageous? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIF stage. ","b":"B.\tFront end RF stage. ","c":"C.\tAudio stage. ","d":"D.\tPower supply"}},{"num":253,"sample":"1F431","correct":"C","question":"Why is the Colpitts oscillator circuit commonly used in a VFO (variable frequency oscillator)? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIt can be phase locked. ","b":"B.\tIt can be remotely tuned. ","c":"C.\tIt is stable. ","d":"D.\tIt has little or no effect on the crystal's stability"}},{"num":254,"sample":"1F432","correct":"A","question":"What is the oscillator stage called in a frequency synthesizer? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tVCO. ","b":"B.\tDivider. ","c":"C.\tPhase detector. ","d":"D.\tReference standard"}},{"num":255,"sample":"1F433","correct":"D","question":"What are three major oscillator circuits found in radio equipment? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tTaft, Pierce, and negative feedback. ","b":"B.\tColpitts, Hartley, and Taft. ","c":"C.\tTaft, Hartley, and Pierce. ","d":"D.\tColpitts, Hartley, and Pierce"}},{"num":256,"sample":"1F434","correct":"A","question":"Which type of oscillator circuit is commonly used in a VFO (variable frequency oscillator)? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tColpitts. ","b":"B.\tPierce. ","c":"C.\tHartley. ","d":"D.\tNegative feedback"}},{"num":257,"sample":"1F435","correct":"D","question":"What condition must exist for a circuit to oscillate?  It must: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tHave a gain of less than 1. ","b":"B.\tBe neutralized. ","c":"C.\tHave sufficient negative feedback. ","d":"D.\tHave sufficient positive feedback"}},{"num":258,"sample":"1F436","correct":"B","question":"In Figure 3F15, which block diagram symbol (labeled 1 through 4) is used to represent a local oscillator? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1. ","b":"B.\t2. ","c":"C.\t3. ","d":"D.\t4"}},{"num":259,"sample":"1F441","correct":"B","question":"What is the image frequency if the normal channel is 151.000 MHz, the IF is operating at 11.000 MHz, and the LO is at 140.000 MHz? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t131.000 MHz. ","b":"B.\t129.000 MHz. ","c":"C.\t162.000 MHz. ","d":"D.\t150.000 MHz"}},{"num":260,"sample":"1F442","correct":"D","question":"What is the mixing process in a radio receiver? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe elimination of noise in a wideband receiver by phase comparison. ","b":"B.\tThe elimination of noise in a wideband receiver by phase differentiation. ","c":"C.\tDistortion caused by auroral propagation. ","d":"D.\tThe combination of two signals to produce sum and difference frequencies"}},{"num":261,"sample":"1F443","correct":"A","question":"In what radio stage is the image frequency normally rejected? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tRF. ","b":"B.\tIF. ","c":"C.\tLO. ","d":"D.\tDetector"}},{"num":262,"sample":"1F444","correct":"C","question":"What are the principal frequencies that appear at the output of a mixer circuit? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tTwo and four times the original frequency. ","b":"B.\tThe sum, difference and square root of the input frequencies. ","c":"C.\tThe original frequencies and the sum and difference frequencies. ","d":"D.\t1.414 and 0.707 times the input frequency"}},{"num":263,"sample":"1F445","correct":"B","question":"If a receiver mixes a 13.8 MHz VFO with a 14.255 MHz receive signal to produce a 455 kHz intermediate frequency signal, what type of interference will a 13.345 MHz signal produce in the receiver? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tLocal oscillator interference. ","b":"B.\tAn image response. ","c":"C.\tMixer interference. ","d":"D.\tIntermediate frequency interference"}},{"num":264,"sample":"1F446","correct":"C","question":"What might occur in a receiver if excessive amounts of signal energy overdrive the mixer circuit? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAutomatic limiting occurs. ","b":"B.\tMixer blanking occurs. ","c":"C.\tSpurious mixer products are generated. ","d":"D.\tThe mixer circuit becomes unstable and drifts"}},{"num":265,"sample":"1F451","correct":"D","question":"What degree of selectivity is desirable in the IF circuitry of a wideband FM phone receiver? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1 kHz. ","b":"B.\t2.4 kHz. ","c":"C.\t4.2 kHz. ","d":"D.\t15 kHz"}},{"num":266,"sample":"1F452","correct":"B","question":"Which one of these filters can be used in micro-miniature electronic circuits? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tHigh power transmitter cavity. ","b":"B.\tReceiver SAW IF filter. ","c":"C.\tFloppy disk controller. ","d":"D.\tInternet DSL to telephone line filter"}},{"num":267,"sample":"1F453","correct":"C","question":"A receiver selectivity of 2.4 kHz in the IF circuitry is optimum for what type of signals? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tCW. ","b":"B.\tDouble-sideband AM voice. ","c":"C.\tSSB voice. ","d":"D.\tFSK RTTY"}},{"num":268,"sample":"1F454","correct":"A","question":"A receiver selectivity of 10 KHz in the IF circuitry is optimum for what type of signals? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tDouble-sideband AM. ","b":"B.\tSSB voice. ","c":"C.\tCW. ","d":"D.\tFSK RTTY"}},{"num":269,"sample":"1F455","correct":"B","question":"What is an undesirable effect of using too wide a filter bandwidth in the IF section of a receiver? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tOutput-offset overshoot. ","b":"B.\tUndesired signals will reach the audio stage. ","c":"C.\tThermal-noise distortion. ","d":"D.\tFilter ringing"}},{"num":270,"sample":"1F456","correct":"A","question":"How should the filter bandwidth of a receiver IF section compare with the bandwidth of a received signal? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tSlightly greater than the received-signal bandwidth. ","b":"B.\tApproximately half the received-signal bandwidth. ","c":"C.\tApproximately two times the received-signal bandwidth. ","d":"D.\tApproximately four times the received-signal bandwidth"}},{"num":271,"sample":"1F461","correct":"B","question":"What is the primary purpose of the final IF amplifier stage in a receiver? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tDynamic response. ","b":"B.\tGain. ","c":"C.\tNoise figure performance. ","d":"D.\tBypass undesired signals"}},{"num":272,"sample":"1F462","correct":"C","question":"What factors should be considered when selecting an intermediate frequency? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tCross-modulation distortion and interference. ","b":"B.\tInterference to other services. ","c":"C.\tImage rejection and selectivity. ","d":"D.\tNoise figure and distortion"}},{"num":273,"sample":"1F463","correct":"D","question":"What is the primary purpose of the first IF amplifier stage in a receiver? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tNoise figure performance. ","b":"B.\tTune out cross-modulation distortion. ","c":"C.\tDynamic response. ","d":"D.\tSelectivity"}},{"num":274,"sample":"1F464","correct":"A","question":"What parameter must be selected when designing an audio filter using an op-amp? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBandpass characteristics. ","b":"B.\tDesired current gain. ","c":"C.\tTemperature coefficient. ","d":"D.\tOutput-offset overshoot"}},{"num":275,"sample":"1F465","correct":"C","question":"What are the distinguishing features of a Chebyshev filter? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIt has a maximally flat response over its passband. ","b":"B.\tIt only requires inductors. ","c":"C.\tIt allows ripple in the passband. ","d":"D.\tA filter whose product of the series- and shunt-element impedances is a constant for all frequencies"}},{"num":276,"sample":"1F466","correct":"D","question":"When would it be more desirable to use an m-derived filter over a constant-k filter? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tWhen the response must be maximally flat at one frequency. ","b":"B.\tWhen the number of components must be minimized. ","c":"C.\tWhen high power levels must be filtered. ","d":"D.\tWhen you need more attenuation at a certain frequency that is too close to the cut-off frequency for a constant-k filter"}},{"num":277,"sample":"1F471","correct":"B","question":"A good crystal band-pass filter for a single-sideband phone would be? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t5 KHz. ","b":"B.\t2.1 KHz. ","c":"C.\t500 Hz. ","d":"D.\t15 KHz"}},{"num":278,"sample":"1F472","correct":"D","question":"Which statement is true regarding the filter output characteristics shown in Figure 3F16? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tC is a low pass curve and B is a band pass curve. ","b":"B.\tB is a high pass curve and D is a low pass curve. ","c":"C.\tA is a high pass curve and B is a low pass curve. ","d":"D.\tA is a low pass curve and D is a band stop curve"}},{"num":279,"sample":"1F473","correct":"A","question":"What are the three general groupings of filters? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tHigh-pass, low-pass and band-pass. ","b":"B.\tInductive, capacitive and resistive. ","c":"C.\tAudio, radio and capacitive. ","d":"D.\tHartley, Colpitts and Pierce"}},{"num":280,"sample":"1F474","correct":"D","question":"What is an m-derived filter? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA filter whose input impedance varies widely over the design bandwidth. ","b":"B.\tA filter whose product of the series- and shunt-element impedances is a constant for all frequencies. ","c":"C.\tA filter whose schematic shape is the letter 'M'. ","d":"D.\tA filter that uses a trap to attenuate undesired frequencies too near cutoff for a constant-k filter"}},{"num":281,"sample":"1F475","correct":"A","question":"What is an advantage of a constant-k filter? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIt has high attenuation of signals at frequencies far removed from the pass band. ","b":"B.\tIt can match impedances over a wide range of frequencies. ","c":"C.\tIt uses elliptic functions. ","d":"D.\tThe ratio of the cutoff frequency to the trap frequency can be varied"}},{"num":282,"sample":"1F476","correct":"C","question":"What are the distinguishing features of a Butterworth filter? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA filter whose product of the series- and shunt-element impedances is a constant for all frequencies. ","b":"B.\tIt only requires capacitors. ","c":"C.\tIt has a maximally flat response over its passband. ","d":"D.\tIt requires only inductors"}},{"num":283,"sample":"1F481","correct":"C","question":"What is a product detector? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIt provides local oscillations for input to the mixer. ","b":"B.\tIt amplifies and narrows the band-pass frequencies. ","c":"C.\tIt uses a mixing process with a locally generated carrier. ","d":"D.\tIt is used to detect cross-modulation products"}},{"num":284,"sample":"1F482","correct":"B","question":"Which circuit is used to detect FM-phone signals? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBalanced modulator. ","b":"B.\tFrequency discriminator. ","c":"C.\tProduct detector. ","d":"D.\tPhase splitter"}},{"num":285,"sample":"1F483","correct":"C","question":"What is the process of detection in a radio diode detector circuit? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBreakdown of the Zener voltage. ","b":"B.\tMixing with noise in the transition region of the diode. ","c":"C.\tRectification and filtering of RF. ","d":"D.\tThe change of reactance in the diode with respect to frequency"}},{"num":286,"sample":"1F484","correct":"A","question":"What is a frequency discriminator in a radio receiver? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA circuit for detecting FM signals. ","b":"B.\tA circuit for filtering two closely adjacent signals. ","c":"C.\tAn automatic band switching circuit. ","d":"D.\tAn FM generator"}},{"num":287,"sample":"1F485","correct":"D","question":"In a CTCSS controlled FM receiver, the CTCSS tone is filtered out after the: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIF stage but before the mixer. ","b":"B.\tMixer but before the IF. ","c":"C.\tIF but before the discriminator. ","d":"D.\tDiscriminator but before the audio section"}},{"num":288,"sample":"1F486","correct":"B","question":"What is the definition of detection in a radio receiver? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe process of masking out the intelligence on a received carrier to make an S-meter operational. ","b":"B.\tThe recovery of intelligence from the modulated RF signal. ","c":"C.\tThe modulation of a carrier. ","d":"D.\tThe mixing of noise with the received signal"}},{"num":289,"sample":"1F491","correct":"A","question":"What is the digital signal processing term for noise subtraction circuitry? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAdaptive filtering and autocorrelation. ","b":"B.\tNoise blanking. ","c":"C.\tNoise limiting. ","d":"D.\tAuto squelch noise reduction"}},{"num":290,"sample":"1F492","correct":"B","question":"What is the purpose of de-emphasis in the receiver audio stage? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tWhen coupled with the transmitter pre-emphasis, flat audio is achieved. ","b":"B.\tWhen coupled with the transmitter pre-emphasis, flat audio and noise reduction is received. ","c":"C.\tNo purpose is achieved. ","d":"D.\tTo conserve bandwidth by squelching no-audio periods in the transmission"}},{"num":291,"sample":"1F493","correct":"D","question":"What makes a Digital Coded Squelch work? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tNoise. ","b":"B.\tTones. ","c":"C.\tAbsence of noise. ","d":"D.\tDigital codes"}},{"num":292,"sample":"1F494","correct":"A","question":"What causes a squelch circuit to function? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tPresence of noise. ","b":"B.\tAbsence of noise. ","c":"C.\tReceived tones. ","d":"D.\tReceived digital codes"}},{"num":293,"sample":"1F495","correct":"B","question":"What makes a CTCSS squelch work? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tNoise. ","b":"B.\tTones. ","c":"C.\tAbsence of noise. ","d":"D.\tDigital codes"}},{"num":294,"sample":"1F496","correct":"C","question":"What radio circuit samples analog signals, records and processes them as numbers, then converts them back to analog signals? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe pre-emphasis audio stage. ","b":"B.\tThe squelch gate circuit. ","c":"C.\tThe digital signal processing circuit. ","d":"D.\tThe voltage controlled oscillator circuit"}},{"num":295,"sample":"1F501","correct":"D","question":"Where would you normally find a low-pass filter in a radio receiver? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIn the AVC circuit. ","b":"B.\tIn the Oscillator stage. ","c":"C.\tIn the Power Supply. ","d":"D.\tA and C, but not B"}},{"num":296,"sample":"1F502","correct":"C","question":"How can ferrite beads be used to suppress ignition noise?  Install them: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIn the resistive high voltage cable every 2 years. ","b":"B.\tBetween the starter solenoid and the starter motor. ","c":"C.\tInstall them in the primary and secondary ignition leads. ","d":"D.\tIn the antenna lead"}},{"num":297,"sample":"1F503","correct":"B","question":"What is the term used to refer to the condition where the signals from a very strong station are superimposed on other signals being received? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIntermodulation distortion. ","b":"B.\tCross-modulation interference. ","c":"C.\tReceiver quieting. ","d":"D.\tCapture effect"}},{"num":298,"sample":"1F504","correct":"C","question":"What is cross-modulation interference? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tInterference between two transmitters of different modulation type. ","b":"B.\tInterference caused by audio rectification in the receiver preamp. ","c":"C.\tModulation from an unwanted signal heard in addition to the desired signal. ","d":"D.\tHarmonic distortion of the transmitted signal"}},{"num":299,"sample":"1F505","correct":"D","question":"In Figure 3F15 at what point in the circuit (labeled 1 through 4) could a DC voltmeter be used to monitor signal strength? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1. ","b":"B.\t2. ","c":"C.\t3. ","d":"D.\t4"}},{"num":300,"sample":"1F506","correct":"A","question":"Pulse type interference to automobile radio receivers that appears related to the speed of the engine can often be reduced by: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tInstalling resistances in series with spark plug wires. ","b":"B.\tUsing heavy conductors between the starting battery and the starting motor. ","c":"C.\tConnecting resistances in series with the battery. ","d":"D.\tGrounding the negative side of the battery"}},{"num":301,"sample":"1G511","correct":"A","question":"What class of amplifier is distinguished by the presence of output throughout the entire signal cycle and the input never goes into the cutoff region? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tClass A. ","b":"B.\tClass B. ","c":"C.\tClass C. ","d":"D.\tClass D"}},{"num":302,"sample":"1G512","correct":"B","question":"What is the distinguishing feature of a Class A amplifier? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tOutput for less than 180 degrees of the signal cycle. ","b":"B.\tOutput for the entire 360 degrees of the signal cycle. ","c":"C.\tOutput for more than 180 degrees and less than 360 degrees of the signal cycle. ","d":"D.\tOutput for exactly 180 degrees of the input signal cycle"}},{"num":303,"sample":"1G513","correct":"A","question":"Which class of amplifier has the highest linearity and least distortion? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tClass A. ","b":"B.\tClass B. ","c":"C.\tClass C. ","d":"D.\tClass AB"}},{"num":304,"sample":"1G514","correct":"C","question":"Which class of amplifier provides the highest efficiency? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tClass A. ","b":"B.\tClass B. ","c":"C.\tClass C. ","d":"D.\tClass AB"}},{"num":305,"sample":"1G515","correct":"B","question":"What class of amplifier is distinguished by the bias being set well beyond cutoff? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tClass A. ","b":"B.\tClass C. ","c":"C.\tClass B. ","d":"D.\tClass AB"}},{"num":306,"sample":"1G516","correct":"D","question":"Which class of amplifier has an operating angle of more than 180 degrees but less than 360 degrees when driven by a sine wave signal? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tClass A. ","b":"B.\tClass B. ","c":"C.\tClass C. ","d":"D.\tClass AB"}},{"num":307,"sample":"1G521","correct":"D","question":"The class B amplifier output is present for what portion of the input cycle? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t360 degrees. ","b":"B.\tGreater than 180 degrees and less than 360 degrees. ","c":"C.\tLess than 180 degrees. ","d":"D.\t180 degrees"}},{"num":308,"sample":"1G522","correct":"C","question":"What input-amplitude parameter is most valuable in evaluating the signal-handling capability of a Class A amplifier? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAverage voltage. ","b":"B.\tRMS voltage. ","c":"C.\tPeak voltage. ","d":"D.\tResting voltage"}},{"num":309,"sample":"1G523","correct":"A","question":"The class C amplifier output is present for what portion of the input cycle? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tLess than 180 degrees. ","b":"B.\tExactly 180 degrees. ","c":"C.\t360 degrees. ","d":"D.\tMore than 180 but less than 360 degrees"}},{"num":310,"sample":"1G524","correct":"D","question":"What is the approximate DC input power to a Class AB RF power amplifier stage in an unmodulated carrier transmitter when the PEP output power is 500 watts? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t250 watts. ","b":"B.\t600 watts. ","c":"C.\t800 watts. ","d":"D.\t1000 watts"}},{"num":311,"sample":"1G525","correct":"C","question":"The class AB amplifier output is present for what portion of the input cycle? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tExactly 180 degrees. ","b":"B.\t360 degrees ","c":"C.\tMore than 180 but less than 360 degrees. ","d":"D.\tLess than 180 degrees"}},{"num":312,"sample":"1G526","correct":"B","question":"What class of amplifier is characterized by conduction for 180 degrees of the input wave? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tClass A. ","b":"B.\tClass B. ","c":"C.\tClass C. ","d":"D.\tClass D"}},{"num":313,"sample":"1G531","correct":"C","question":"What is the modulation index in an FM phone signal having a maximum frequency deviation of 3,000 Hz on either side of the carrier frequency when the modulating frequency is 1,000 Hz? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t0.3. ","b":"B.\t3,000. ","c":"C.\t3. ","d":"D.\t1,000"}},{"num":314,"sample":"1G532","correct":"A","question":"What is the modulation index of a FM phone transmitter producing a maximum carrier deviation of 6 kHz when modulated with a 2 kHz modulating frequency? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t3. ","b":"B.\t6,000. ","c":"C.\t2,000. ","d":"D.\t1"}},{"num":315,"sample":"1G533","correct":"D","question":"What is the total bandwidth of a FM phone transmission having a 5 kHz deviation and a 3 kHz modulating frequency? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t3 kHz. ","b":"B.\t8 kHz. ","c":"C.\t5 kHz. ","d":"D.\t16 kHz"}},{"num":316,"sample":"1G534","correct":"A","question":"How does the modulation index of a phase-modulated emission vary with RF carrier frequency? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIt does not depend on the RF carrier frequency. ","b":"B.\tModulation index increases as the RF carrier frequency increases. ","c":"C.\tIt varies with the square root of the RF carrier frequency. ","d":"D.\tIt decreases as the RF carrier frequency increases"}},{"num":317,"sample":"1G535","correct":"D","question":"How can a single-sideband phone signal be generated? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBy driving a product detector with a DSB signal. ","b":"B.\tBy using a reactance modulator followed by a mixer. ","c":"C.\tBy using a loop modulator followed by a mixer. ","d":"D.\tBy using a balanced modulator followed by a filter"}},{"num":318,"sample":"1G536","correct":"B","question":"What is a balanced modulator? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAn FM modulator that produces a balanced deviation. ","b":"B.\tA modulator that produces a double sideband, suppressed carrier signal. ","c":"C.\tA modulator that produces a single sideband, suppressed carrier signal. ","d":"D.\tA modulator that produces a full carrier signal"}},{"num":319,"sample":"1G541","correct":"B","question":"What is an L-network? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA low power Wi-Fi RF network connection. ","b":"B.\tA network consisting of an inductor and a capacitor. ","c":"C.\tA 'lossy' network. ","d":"D.\tA network formed by joining two low pass filters"}},{"num":320,"sample":"1G542","correct":"D","question":"What is a pi-network? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA network consisting of a capacitor, resistor and inductor. ","b":"B.\tThe Phase inversion stage. ","c":"C.\tAn enhanced token ring network. ","d":"D.\tA network consisting of one inductor and two capacitors or two inductors and one capacitor"}},{"num":321,"sample":"1G543","correct":"A","question":"What is the resonant frequency in an electrical circuit? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe frequency at which capacitive reactance equals inductive reactance. ","b":"B.\tThe highest frequency that will pass current. ","c":"C.\tThe lowest frequency that will pass current. ","d":"D.\tThe frequency at which power factor is at a minimum"}},{"num":322,"sample":"1G544","correct":"C","question":"Which three network types are commonly used to match an amplifying device to a transmission line? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tPi-C network, pi network and T network. ","b":"B.\tT network, M network and Z network. ","c":"C.\tL network, pi network and pi-L network. ","d":"D.\tL network, pi network and C network"}},{"num":323,"sample":"1G545","correct":"B","question":"What is a pi-L network? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA Phase Inverter Load network. ","b":"B.\tA network consisting of two inductors and two capacitors. ","c":"C.\tA network with only three discrete parts. ","d":"D.\tA matching network in which all components are isolated from ground"}},{"num":324,"sample":"1G546","correct":"C","question":"Which network provides the greatest harmonic suppression? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tL network. ","b":"B.\tPi network. ","c":"C.\tPi-L network. ","d":"D.\tInverse L network"}},{"num":325,"sample":"1G551","correct":"D","question":"What will occur when a non-linear amplifier is used with a single-sideband phone transmitter? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tReduced amplifier efficiency. ","b":"B.\tIncreased intelligibility. ","c":"C.\tSideband inversion. ","d":"D.\tDistortion"}},{"num":326,"sample":"1G552","correct":"B","question":"To produce a single-sideband suppressed carrier transmission it is necessary to ____ the carrier and to ____ the unwanted sideband. ","answers":{"a":"A.\tFilter, filter. ","b":"B.\tCancel, filter. ","c":"C.\tFilter, cancel. ","d":"D.\tCancel, cancel"}},{"num":327,"sample":"1G553","correct":"C","question":"In a single-sideband phone signal, what determines the PEP-to-average power ratio? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe frequency of the modulating signal. ","b":"B.\tThe degree of carrier suppression. ","c":"C.\tThe speech characteristics. ","d":"D.\tThe amplifier power"}},{"num":328,"sample":"1G554","correct":"A","question":"What is the approximate ratio of peak envelope power to average power during normal voice modulation peak in a single-sideband phone signal? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t2.5 to 1. ","b":"B.\t1 to 1. ","c":"C.\t25 to 1. ","d":"D.\t100 to 1"}},{"num":329,"sample":"1G555","correct":"B","question":"What is the output peak envelope power from a transmitter as measured on an oscilloscope showing 200 volts peak-to-peak across a 50-ohm load resistor? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1,000 watts. ","b":"B.\t100 watts. ","c":"C.\t200 watts. ","d":"D.\t400 watts"}},{"num":330,"sample":"1G556","correct":"A","question":"What would be the voltage across a 50-ohm dummy load dissipating 1,200 watts? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t245 volts. ","b":"B.\t692 volts. ","c":"C.\t346 volts. ","d":"D.\t173 volts"}},{"num":331,"sample":"1G561","correct":"B","question":"How can intermodulation interference between two transmitters in close proximity often be reduced or eliminated? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBy using a Class C final amplifier with high driving power. ","b":"B.\tBy installing a terminated circulator or ferrite isolator in the feed line to the transmitter and duplexer. ","c":"C.\tBy installing a band-pass filter in the antenna feed line. ","d":"D.\tBy installing a low-pass filter in the antenna feed line"}},{"num":332,"sample":"1G562","correct":"C","question":"How can parasitic oscillations be eliminated in a power amplifier? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBy tuning for maximum SWR. ","b":"B.\tBy tuning for maximum power output. ","c":"C.\tBy neutralization. ","d":"D.\tBy tuning the output"}},{"num":333,"sample":"1G563","correct":"D","question":"What is the name of the condition that occurs when the signals of two transmitters in close proximity mix together in one or both of their final amplifiers, and unwanted signals at the sum and difference frequencies of the original transmissions are generated? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAmplifier desensitization. ","b":"B.\tNeutralization. ","c":"C.\tAdjacent channel interference. ","d":"D.\tIntermodulation interference"}},{"num":334,"sample":"1G564","correct":"A","question":"What term describes a wide-bandwidth communications system in which the RF carrier varies according to some pre-determined sequence? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tSpread-spectrum communication. ","b":"B.\tAMTOR. ","c":"C.\tSITOR. ","d":"D.\tTime-domain frequency modulation"}},{"num":335,"sample":"1G565","correct":"C","question":"How can even-order harmonics be reduced or prevented in transmitter amplifier design? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBy using a push-push amplifier. ","b":"B.\tBy operating class C. ","c":"C.\tBy using a push-pull amplifier. ","d":"D.\tBy operating class AB"}},{"num":336,"sample":"1G566","correct":"D","question":"What is the modulation type that can be a frequency hopping of one carrier or multiple simultaneous carriers? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tSSB. ","b":"B.\tFM. ","c":"C.\tOFSK. ","d":"D.\tSpread spectrum"}},{"num":337,"sample":"1H571","correct":"B","question":"The deviation ratio is the: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAudio modulating frequency to the center carrier frequency. ","b":"B.\tMaximum carrier frequency deviation to the highest audio modulating frequency. ","c":"C.\tCarrier center frequency to the audio modulating frequency. ","d":"D.\tHighest audio modulating frequency to the average audio modulating frequency"}},{"num":338,"sample":"1H572","correct":"D","question":"What is the deviation ratio for an FM phone signal having a maximum frequency deviation of plus or minus 5 kHz and accepting a maximum modulation rate of 3 kHz? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t60. ","b":"B.\t0.16. ","c":"C.\t0.6. ","d":"D.\t1.66"}},{"num":339,"sample":"1H573","correct":"A","question":"What is the deviation ratio of an FM-phone signal having a maximum frequency swing of plus or minus 7.5 kHz and accepting a maximum modulation rate of 3.5 kHz? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t2.14. ","b":"B.\t0.214. ","c":"C.\t0.47. ","d":"D.\t47"}},{"num":340,"sample":"1H574","correct":"D","question":"How can an FM-phone signal be produced in a transmitter? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBy modulating the supply voltage to a class-B amplifier. ","b":"B.\tBy modulating the supply voltage to a class-C amplifier. ","c":"C.\tBy using a balanced modulator. ","d":"D.\tBy feeding the audio directly to the oscillator"}},{"num":341,"sample":"1H575","correct":"A","question":"What is meant by the term modulation index? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe ratio between the deviation of a frequency modulated signal and the modulating frequency. ","b":"B.\tThe processor index. ","c":"C.\tThe FM signal-to-noise ratio. ","d":"D.\tThe ratio of the maximum carrier frequency deviation to the highest audio modulating frequency"}},{"num":342,"sample":"1H576","correct":"C","question":"In an FM-phone signal, what is the term for the maximum deviation from the carrier frequency divided by the maximum audio modulating frequency? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tDeviation index. ","b":"B.\tModulation index. ","c":"C.\tDeviation ratio. ","d":"D.\tModulation ratio"}},{"num":343,"sample":"1H581","correct":"C","question":"In Figure 3H17, the block labeled 4 would indicate that this schematic is most likely a/an: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAudio amplifier. ","b":"B.\tShipboard RADAR. ","c":"C.\tSSB radio transmitter. ","d":"D.\tWireless LAN (local area network) computer"}},{"num":344,"sample":"1H582","correct":"B","question":"In Figure 3H17, which block diagram symbol (labeled 1 through 4) represents where audio intelligence is inserted? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1. ","b":"B.\t2. ","c":"C.\t3. ","d":"D.\t4"}},{"num":345,"sample":"1H583","correct":"C","question":"What kind of input signal could be used to test the amplitude linearity of a single-sideband phone transmitter while viewing the output on an oscilloscope? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tWhistling in the microphone. ","b":"B.\tAn audio frequency sine wave. ","c":"C.\tA two-tone audio-frequency sine wave. ","d":"D.\tAn audio frequency square wave"}},{"num":346,"sample":"1H584","correct":"A","question":"What does a two-tone test illustrate on an oscilloscope? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tLinearity of a SSB transmitter. ","b":"B.\tFrequency of the carrier phase shift. ","c":"C.\tPercentage of frequency modulation. ","d":"D.\tSideband suppression"}},{"num":347,"sample":"1H585","correct":"D","question":"How can a double-sideband phone signal be produced? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBy using a reactance modulator. ","b":"B.\tBy varying the voltage to the varactor in an oscillator circuit. ","c":"C.\tBy using a phase detector, oscillator, and filter in a feedback loop. ","d":"D.\tBy modulating the supply voltage to a class C amplifier"}},{"num":348,"sample":"1H586","correct":"B","question":"What type of signals are used to conduct an SSB two-tone test? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tTwo audio signals of the same frequency, but shifted 90 degrees in phase. ","b":"B.\tTwo non-harmonically related audio signals that are within the modulation band pass of the transmitter. ","c":"C.\tTwo different audio frequency square wave signals of equal amplitude. ","d":"D.\tAny two audio frequencies as long as they are harmonically related"}},{"num":349,"sample":"1H591","correct":"A","question":"What is an important factor in pulse-code modulation using time-division multiplex? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tSynchronization of transmit and receive clock pulse rates. ","b":"B.\tFrequency separation. ","c":"C.\tOvermodulation and undermodulation. ","d":"D.\tSlight variations in power supply voltage"}},{"num":350,"sample":"1H592","correct":"B","question":"In a pulse-width modulation system, what parameter does the modulating signal vary? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tPulse frequency. ","b":"B.\tPulse duration. ","c":"C.\tPulse amplitude. ","d":"D.\tPulse intensity"}},{"num":351,"sample":"1H593","correct":"D","question":"What is the name of the type of modulation in which the modulating signal varies the duration of the transmitted pulse? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAmplitude modulation. ","b":"B.\tFrequency modulation. ","c":"C.\tPulse-height modulation. ","d":"D.\tPulse-width modulation"}},{"num":352,"sample":"1H594","correct":"A","question":"Which of the following best describes a pulse modulation system? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe peak transmitter power is normally much greater than the average power. ","b":"B.\tPulse modulation is sometimes used in SSB voice transmitters. ","c":"C.\tThe average power is normally only slightly below the peak power. ","d":"D.\tThe peak power is normally twice as high as the average power"}},{"num":353,"sample":"1H595","correct":"B","question":"In a pulse-position modulation system, what parameter does the modulating signal vary? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe number of pulses per second. ","b":"B.\tThe time at which each pulse occurs. ","c":"C.\tBoth the frequency and amplitude of the pulses. ","d":"D.\tThe duration of the pulses"}},{"num":354,"sample":"1H596","correct":"C","question":"What is one way that voice is transmitted in a pulse-width modulation system? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA standard pulse is varied in amplitude by an amount depending on the voice waveform at that instant. ","b":"B.\tThe position of a standard pulse is varied by an amount depending on the voice waveform at that instant. ","c":"C.\tA standard pulse is varied in duration by an amount depending on the voice waveform at that instant. ","d":"D.\tThe number of standard pulses per second varies depending on the voice waveform at that instant"}},{"num":355,"sample":"1I601","correct":"D","question":"When a lead-acid storage battery is being charged, a harmful effect to humans is: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tInternal plate sulfation may occur under constant charging. ","b":"B.\tEmission of oxygen. ","c":"C.\tEmission of chlorine gas. ","d":"D.\tEmission of hydrogen gas"}},{"num":356,"sample":"1I602","correct":"C","question":"A battery with a terminal voltage of 12.5 volts is to be trickle-charged at a 0.5 A rate. What resistance should be connected in series with the battery to charge it from a 110-V DC line? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t95 ohms. ","b":"B.\t300 ohms. ","c":"C.\t195 ohms. ","d":"D.\tNone of these"}},{"num":357,"sample":"1I603","correct":"B","question":"What capacity in amperes does a storage battery need to be in order to operate a 50 watt transmitter for 6 hours? Assume a continuous transmitter load of 70% of the key-locked demand of 40 A, and an emergency light load of 1.5 A. ","answers":{"a":"A.\t100 ampere-hours. ","b":"B.\t177 ampere-hours. ","c":"C.\t249 ampere-hours. ","d":"D.\tNone of these"}},{"num":358,"sample":"1I604","correct":"C","question":"What is the total voltage when 12 Nickel-Cadmium batteries are connected in series? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t12 volts. ","b":"B.\t12.6 volts. ","c":"C.\t15 volts. ","d":"D.\t72 volts"}},{"num":359,"sample":"1I605","correct":"D","question":"The average fully-charged voltage of a lead-acid storage cell is: ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1 volt. ","b":"B.\t1.2 volts. ","c":"C.\t1.56 volts. ","d":"D.\t2.06 volts"}},{"num":360,"sample":"1I606","correct":"A","question":"A nickel-cadmium cell has an operating voltage of about: ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1.25 volts. ","b":"B.\t1.4 volts. ","c":"C.\t1.5 volts. ","d":"D.\t2.1 volts"}},{"num":361,"sample":"1I611","correct":"A","question":"When an emergency transmitter uses 325 watts and a receiver uses 50 watts, how many hours can a 12.6 volt, 55 ampere-hour battery supply full power to both units? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1.8 hours. ","b":"B.\t6 hours. ","c":"C.\t3 hours. ","d":"D.\t1.2 hours"}},{"num":362,"sample":"1I612","correct":"B","question":"What current will flow in a 6 volt storage battery with an internal resistance of 0.01 ohms, when a 3-watt, 6-volt lamp is connected? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t0.4885 amps. ","b":"B.\t0.4995 amps. ","c":"C.\t0.5566 amps. ","d":"D.\t0.5795 amps"}},{"num":363,"sample":"1I613","correct":"A","question":"A ship RADAR unit uses 315 watts and a radio uses 50 watts.  If the equipment is connected to a 50 ampere-hour battery rated at 12.6 volts, how long will the battery last? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1 hour 43 minutes. ","b":"B.\t28.97 hours. ","c":"C.\t29 minutes. ","d":"D.\t10 hours, 50 minutes"}},{"num":364,"sample":"1I614","correct":"C","question":"If a marine radiotelephone receiver uses 75 watts of power and a transmitter uses 325 watts, how long can they both operate before discharging a 50 ampere-hour 12 volt battery? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t40 minutes. ","b":"B.\t1 hour. ","c":"C.\t1 1/2 hours. ","d":"D.\t6 hours"}},{"num":365,"sample":"1I615","correct":"B","question":"A 6 volt battery with 1.2 ohms internal resistance is connected across two light bulbs in parallel whose resistance is 12 ohms each.  What is the current flow? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t0.57 amps. ","b":"B.\t0.83 amps. ","c":"C.\t1.0 amps. ","d":"D.\t6.0 amps"}},{"num":366,"sample":"1I616","correct":"D","question":"A 12.6 volt, 8 ampere-hour battery is supplying power to a receiver that uses 50 watts and a RADAR system that uses 300 watts.  How long will the battery last? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t100.8 hours. ","b":"B.\t27.7 hours. ","c":"C.\t1 hour. ","d":"D.\t17 minutes or 0.3 hours"}},{"num":367,"sample":"1I621","correct":"D","question":"What occurs if the load is removed from an operating series DC motor? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIt will stop running. ","b":"B.\tSpeed will increase slightly. ","c":"C.\tNo change occurs. ","d":"D.\tIt will accelerate until it falls apart"}},{"num":368,"sample":"1I622","correct":"C","question":"If a shunt motor running with a load has its shunt field opened, how would this affect the speed of the motor? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIt will slow down. ","b":"B.\tIt will stop suddenly. ","c":"C.\tIt will speed up. ","d":"D.\tIt will be unaffected"}},{"num":369,"sample":"1I623","correct":"A","question":"The expression 'voltage regulation' as it applies to a shunt-wound DC generator operating at a constant frequency refers to: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tVoltage fluctuations from load to no-load. ","b":"B.\tVoltage output efficiency. ","c":"C.\tVoltage in the secondary compared to the primary. ","d":"D.\tRotor winding voltage ratio "}},{"num":370,"sample":"1I624","correct":"D","question":"What is the line current of a 7 horsepower motor operating on 120 volts at full load, a power factor of 0.8, and 95% efficient? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t4.72 amps. ","b":"B.\t13.03 amps. ","c":"C.\t56 amps. ","d":"D.\t57.2 amps"}},{"num":371,"sample":"1I625","correct":"C","question":"A 3 horsepower, 100 V DC motor is 85% efficient when developing its rated output. What is the current? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t8.545 amps. ","b":"B.\t20.345 amps. ","c":"C.\t26.300 amps. ","d":"D.\t25.000 amps"}},{"num":372,"sample":"1I626","correct":"B","question":"The output of a separately-excited AC generator running at a constant speed can be controlled by: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe armature. ","b":"B.\tThe amount of field current. ","c":"C.\tThe brushes. ","d":"D.\tThe exciter"}},{"num":373,"sample":"1J631","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following could cause a high standing wave ratio on a transmission line? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tExcessive modulation. ","b":"B.\tAn increase in output power. ","c":"C.\tA detuned antenna coupler. ","d":"D.\tLow power from the transmitter"}},{"num":374,"sample":"1J632","correct":"A","question":"Why is the value of the radiation resistance of an antenna important? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tKnowing the radiation resistance makes it possible to match impedances for maximum power transfer. ","b":"B.\tKnowing the radiation resistance makes it possible to measure the near-field radiation density from transmitting antenna. ","c":"C.\tThe value of the radiation resistance represents the front-to-side ratio of the antenna. ","d":"D.\tThe value of the radiation resistance represents the front-to-back ratio of the antenna"}},{"num":375,"sample":"1J633","correct":"D","question":"A radio frequency device that allows RF energy to pass through in one direction with very little loss but absorbs RF power in the opposite direction is a: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tCirculator. ","b":"B.\tWave trap. ","c":"C.\tMultiplexer. ","d":"D.\tIsolator"}},{"num":376,"sample":"1J634","correct":"A","question":"What is an advantage of using a trap antenna? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIt may be used for multiband operation. ","b":"B.\tIt has high directivity in the high-frequency bands. ","c":"C.\tIt has high gain. ","d":"D.\tIt minimizes harmonic radiation"}},{"num":377,"sample":"1J635","correct":"D","question":"What is meant by the term radiation resistance of an antenna? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tLosses in the antenna elements and feed line. ","b":"B.\tThe specific impedance of the antenna. ","c":"C.\tThe resistance in the trap coils to received signals. ","d":"D.\tAn equivalent resistance that would dissipate the same amount of power as that radiated from an antenna"}},{"num":378,"sample":"1J636","correct":"B","question":"What is meant by the term antenna bandwidth? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAntenna length divided by the number of elements. ","b":"B.\tThe frequency range over which an antenna can be expected to perform well. ","c":"C.\tThe angle between the half-power radiation points. ","d":"D.\tThe angle formed between two imaginary lines drawn through the ends of the elements"}},{"num":379,"sample":"1J641","correct":"B","question":"What is the current flowing through a 52 ohm line with an input of 1,872 watts? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t0.06 amps. ","b":"B.\t6 amps. ","c":"C.\t28.7 amps. ","d":"D.\t144 amps"}},{"num":380,"sample":"1J642","correct":"D","question":"The voltage produced in a receiving antenna is: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tOut of phase with the current if connected properly. ","b":"B.\tOut of phase with the current if cut to 1/3 wavelength. ","c":"C.\tVariable depending on the station's SWR. ","d":"D.\tAlways proportional to the received field strength"}},{"num":381,"sample":"1J643","correct":"A","question":"Which of the following represents the best standing wave ratio (SWR)? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1:1. ","b":"B.\t1:1.5. ","c":"C.\t1:3. ","d":"D.\t1:4"}},{"num":382,"sample":"1J644","correct":"C","question":"At the ends of a half-wave antenna, what values of current and voltage exist compared to the remainder of the antenna? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tEqual voltage and current. ","b":"B.\tMinimum voltage and maximum current. ","c":"C.\tMaximum voltage and minimum current. ","d":"D.\tMinimum voltage and minimum current"}},{"num":383,"sample":"1J645","correct":"B","question":"An antenna radiates a primary signal of 500 watts output.  If there is a 2nd harmonic output of 0.5 watt, what attenuation of the 2nd harmonic has occurred? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t10 dB. ","b":"B.\t30 dB. ","c":"C.\t40 dB. ","d":"D.\t50 dB"}},{"num":384,"sample":"1J646","correct":"C","question":"There is an improper impedance match between a 30 watt transmitter and the antenna, with 5 watts reflected. How much power is actually radiated? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t35 watts. ","b":"B.\t30 watts. ","c":"C.\t25 watts. ","d":"D.\t20 watts"}},{"num":385,"sample":"1J651","correct":"D","question":"A vertical 1/4 wave antenna receives signals: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIn the microwave band. ","b":"B.\tIn one vertical direction. ","c":"C.\tIn one horizontal direction. ","d":"D.\tEqually from all horizontal directions"}},{"num":386,"sample":"1J652","correct":"B","question":"The resonant frequency of a Hertz antenna can be lowered by: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tLowering the frequency of the transmitter. ","b":"B.\tPlacing an inductance in series with the antenna. ","c":"C.\tPlacing a condenser in series with the antenna. ","d":"D.\tPlacing a resistor in series with the antenna"}},{"num":387,"sample":"1J653","correct":"C","question":"An excited 1/2 wavelength antenna produces: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tResidual fields. ","b":"B.\tAn electro-magnetic field only. ","c":"C.\tBoth electro-magnetic and electro-static fields. ","d":"D.\tAn electro-flux field sometimes"}},{"num":388,"sample":"1J654","correct":"A","question":"To increase the resonant frequency of a 1/4 wavelength antenna: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAdd a capacitor in series. ","b":"B.\tLower capacitor value. ","c":"C.\tCut antenna. ","d":"D.\tAdd an inductor"}},{"num":389,"sample":"1J655","correct":"B","question":"What happens to the bandwidth of an antenna as it is shortened through the use of loading coils? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIt is increased. ","b":"B.\tIt is decreased. ","c":"C.\tNo change occurs. ","d":"D.\tIt becomes flat"}},{"num":390,"sample":"1J656","correct":"A","question":"To lengthen an antenna electrically, add a: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tCoil. ","b":"B.\tResistor. ","c":"C.\tBattery. ","d":"D.\tConduit"}},{"num":391,"sample":"1J661","correct":"B","question":"What is the meaning of the term velocity factor of a transmission line? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe ratio of the characteristic impedance of the line to the terminating impedance. ","b":"B.\tThe velocity of the wave on the transmission line divided by the velocity of light in a vacuum. ","c":"C.\tThe velocity of the wave on the transmission line multiplied by the velocity of light in a vacuum. ","d":"D.\tThe index of shielding for coaxial cable"}},{"num":392,"sample":"1J662","correct":"C","question":"What determines the velocity factor in a transmission line? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe termination impedance. ","b":"B.\tThe line length. ","c":"C.\tDielectrics in the line. ","d":"D.\tThe center conductor resistivity"}},{"num":393,"sample":"1J663","correct":"D","question":"Nitrogen is placed in transmission lines to: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tImprove the 'skin-effect' of microwaves. ","b":"B.\tReduce arcing in the line. ","c":"C.\tReduce the standing wave ratio of the line. ","d":"D.\tPrevent moisture from entering the line"}},{"num":394,"sample":"1J664","correct":"A","question":"A perfect (no loss) coaxial cable has 7 dB of reflected power when the input is 5 watts. What is the output of the transmission line? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1 watt. ","b":"B.\t1.25 watts. ","c":"C.\t2.5 watts. ","d":"D.\t5 watts"}},{"num":395,"sample":"1J665","correct":"C","question":"Referred to the fundamental frequency, a shorted stub line attached to the transmission line to absorb even harmonics could have a wavelength of: ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1.41 wavelength. ","b":"B.\t1/2 wavelength. ","c":"C.\t1/4 wavelength. ","d":"D.\t1/6 wavelength"}},{"num":396,"sample":"1J666","correct":"D","question":"If a transmission line has a power loss of 6 dB per 100 feet, what is the power at the feed point to the antenna at the end of a 200 foot transmission line fed by a 100 watt transmitter? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t70 watts. ","b":"B.\t50 watts. ","c":"C.\t25 watts. ","d":"D.\t6 watts"}},{"num":397,"sample":"1J671","correct":"B","question":"What is the effective radiated power of a repeater with 50 watts transmitter power output, 4 dB feedline loss, 3 dB duplexer and circulator loss, and 6 dB antenna gain? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t158 watts. ","b":"B.\t39.7 watts. ","c":"C.\t251 watts. ","d":"D.\t69.9 watts"}},{"num":398,"sample":"1J672","correct":"D","question":"What is the effective radiated power of a repeater with 75 watts transmitter power output, 4 dB feedline loss, 3 dB duplexer and circulator loss, and 10 dB antenna gain? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t600 watts. ","b":"B.\t75 watts. ","c":"C.\t18.75 watts. ","d":"D.\t150 watts"}},{"num":399,"sample":"1J673","correct":"A","question":"What is the effective radiated power of a repeater with 75 watts transmitter power output, 5 dB feedline loss, 4 dB duplexer and circulator loss, and 6 dB antenna gain? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t37.6 watts. ","b":"B.\t237 watts. ","c":"C.\t150 watts. ","d":"D.\t23.7 watts"}},{"num":400,"sample":"1J674","correct":"D","question":"What is the effective radiated power of a repeater with 100 watts transmitter power output, 4 dB feedline loss, 3 dB duplexer and circulator loss, and 7 dB antenna gain? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t631 watts. ","b":"B.\t400 watts. ","c":"C.\t25 watts. ","d":"D.\t100 watts"}},{"num":401,"sample":"1J675","correct":"A","question":"What is the effective radiated power of a repeater with 100 watts transmitter power output, 5 dB feedline loss, 4 dB duplexer and circulator loss, and 10 dB antenna gain? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t126 watts. ","b":"B.\t800 watts. ","c":"C.\t12.5 watts. ","d":"D.\t1260 watts"}},{"num":402,"sample":"1J676","correct":"C","question":"What is the effective radiated power of a repeater with 50 watts transmitter power output, 5 dB feedline loss, 4 dB duplexer and circulator loss, and 7 dB antenna gain? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t300 watts. ","b":"B.\t315 watts. ","c":"C.\t31.5 watts. ","d":"D.\t69.9 watts"}},{"num":403,"sample":"1K681","correct":"C","question":"What is the frequency range of the Distance Measuring Equipment (DME) used to indicate an aircraft's slant range distance to a selected ground-based navigation station? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t108.00 MHz to 117.95 MHz. ","b":"B.\t108.10 MHz to 111.95 MHz. ","c":"C.\t962 MHz to 1213 MHz. ","d":"D.\t329.15 MHz to 335.00 MHz"}},{"num":404,"sample":"1K682","correct":"B","question":"The Distance Measuring Equipment (DME) measures the distance from the aircraft to the DME ground station. This is referred to as: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tDME bearing. ","b":"B.\tThe slant range. ","c":"C.\tGlide Slope angle of approach. ","d":"D.\tLocalizer course width"}},{"num":405,"sample":"1K683","correct":"C","question":"The Distance Measuring Equipment (DME) ground station has a built-in delay between reception of an interrogation and transmission of the reply to allow: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tSomeone to answer the call. ","b":"B.\tThe VOR to make a mechanical hook-up. ","c":"C.\tOperation at close range. ","d":"D.\tClear other traffic for a reply"}},{"num":406,"sample":"1K684","correct":"A","question":"What is the main underlying operating principle of an aircraft's Distance Measuring Equipment (DME)? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA measurable amount of time is required to send and receive a radio signal through the Earth's atmosphere. ","b":"B.\tThe difference between the peak values of two DC voltages may be used to determine an aircraft's distance to another aircraft. ","c":"C.\tA measurable frequency compression of an AC signal may be used to determine an aircraft's altitude above the earth. ","d":"D.\tA phase inversion between two AC voltages may be used to determine an aircraft's distance to the exit ramp of an airport's runway"}},{"num":407,"sample":"1K685","correct":"D","question":"What radio navigation aid determines the distance from an aircraft to a selected VORTAC station by measuring the length of time the radio signal takes to travel to and from the station? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tRADAR. ","b":"B.\tLoran C. ","c":"C.\tDistance Marking (DM). ","d":"D.\tDistance Measuring Equipment (DME)"}},{"num":408,"sample":"1K686","correct":"B","question":"The majority of airborne Distance Measuring Equipment systems automatically tune their transmitter and receiver frequencies to the paired __ / __ channel. ","answers":{"a":"A.\tVOR/marker beacon. ","b":"B.\tVOR/LOC. ","c":"C.\tMarker beacon/glideslope. ","d":"D.\tLOC/glideslope"}},{"num":409,"sample":"1K691","correct":"A","question":"All directions associated with a VOR station are related to: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tMagnetic north. ","b":"B.\tNorth pole. ","c":"C.\tNorth star. ","d":"D.\tNone of these"}},{"num":410,"sample":"1K692","correct":"B","question":"The rate that the transmitted VOR variable signal rotates is equivalent to how many revolutions per second? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t60. ","b":"B.\t30. ","c":"C.\t2400. ","d":"D.\t1800"}},{"num":411,"sample":"1K693","correct":"D","question":"What is the frequency range of the ground-based Very-high-frequency Omnidirectional Range (VOR) stations used for aircraft navigation? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t108.00 kHz to 117.95 kHz. ","b":"B.\t329.15 MHz to 335.00 MHz. ","c":"C.\t329.15 kHz to 335.00 kHz. ","d":"D.\t108.00 MHz to 117.95 MHz"}},{"num":412,"sample":"1K694","correct":"A","question":"Lines drawn from the VOR station in a particular magnetic direction are: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tRadials. ","b":"B.\tQuadrants. ","c":"C.\tBearings. ","d":"D.\tHeadings"}},{"num":413,"sample":"1K695","correct":"B","question":"The amplitude modulated variable phase signal and the frequency modulated reference phase signal of a Very-high-frequency Omnidirectional Range (VOR) station used for aircraft navigation are synchronized so that both signals are in phase with each other at ____________ of the VOR station. ","answers":{"a":"A.\t180 degrees South, true bearing position. ","b":"B.\t360 degrees North, magnetic bearing position. ","c":"C.\t180 degrees South, magnetic bearing position. ","d":"D.\t0 degrees North, true bearing position"}},{"num":414,"sample":"1K696","correct":"C","question":"What is the main underlying operating principle of the Very-high-frequency Omnidirectional Range (VOR) aircraft navigational system? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA definite amount of time is required to send and receive a radio signal. ","b":"B.\tThe difference between the peak values of two DC voltages may be used to determine an aircraft's altitude above a selected VOR station. ","c":"C.\tA phase difference between two AC voltages may be used to determine an aircraft's azimuth position in relation to a selected VOR station. ","d":"D.\tA phase difference between two AC voltages may be used to determine an aircraft's distance from a selected VOR station"}},{"num":415,"sample":"1K701","correct":"D","question":"What is the frequency range of the localizer beam system used by aircraft to find the centerline of a runway during an Instrument Landing System (ILS) approach to an airport? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t108.10 kHz to 111.95 kHz. ","b":"B.\t329.15 MHz to 335.00 MHz. ","c":"C.\t329.15 kHz to 335.00 kHz. ","d":"D.\t108.10 MHz to 111.95 MHz"}},{"num":416,"sample":"1K702","correct":"C","question":"What is the frequency range of the marker beacon system used to indicate an aircraft's position during an Instrument Landing System (ILS) approach to an airport's runway? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe outer, middle, and inner marker beacons' UHF frequencies are unique for each ILS equipped airport to provide unambiguous frequency-protected reception areas in the 329.15 to 335.00 MHz range. ","b":"B.\tThe outer marker beacon's carrier frequency is 400 MHz, the middle marker beacon's carrier frequency is 1300 MHz, and the inner marker beacon's carrier frequency is 3000 MHz. ","c":"C.\tThe outer, the middle, and the inner marker beacon's carrier frequencies are all 75 MHz but the marker beacons are 95% tone-modulated at 400 Hz (outer), 1300 Hz (middle), and 3000 Hz (inner). ","d":"D.\tThe outer, marker beacon's carrier frequency is 3000 kHz, the middle marker beacon's carrier frequency is 1300 kHz, and the inner marker beacon's carrier frequency is 400 kHz"}},{"num":417,"sample":"1K703","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following is a required component of an Instrument Landing System (ILS)? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAltimeter: shows aircraft height above sea-level. ","b":"B.\tLocalizer: shows aircraft deviation horizontally from center of runway. ","c":"C.\tVHF Communications: provide communications to aircraft. ","d":"D.\tDistance Measuring Equipment: shows aircraft distance to VORTAC station"}},{"num":418,"sample":"1K704","correct":"C","question":"What type of antenna is used in an aircraft's Instrument Landing System (ILS) glideslope installation? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA vertically polarized antenna that radiates an omnidirectional antenna pattern. ","b":"B.\tA balanced loop reception antenna. ","c":"C.\tA folded dipole reception antenna. ","d":"D.\tAn electronically steerable phased-array antenna that radiates a directional antenna pattern"}},{"num":419,"sample":"1K705","correct":"D","question":"Choose the only correct statement about the localizer beam system used by aircraft to find the centerline of a runway during an Instrument Landing System (ILS) approach to an airport.  The localizer beam system: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tOperates within the assigned frequency range of 108.10 to 111.95 GHz. ","b":"B.\tProduces two amplitude modulated antenna patterns; one pattern above and one pattern below the normal 2.5 degree approach glide path of the aircraft. ","c":"C.\tFrequencies are automatically tuned-in when the proper glide slope frequency is selected on the aircraft's Navigation and Communication (NAV/COMM) transceiver. ","d":"D.\tProduces two amplitude modulated antenna patterns; one pattern with an audio frequency of 90 Hz and one pattern with an audio frequency of 150 Hz, one left of the runway centerline and one right of the runway centerline"}},{"num":420,"sample":"1K706","correct":"A","question":"On runway approach, an ILS Localizer shows: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tDeviation left or right of runway center line. ","b":"B.\tDeviation up and down from ground speed. ","c":"C.\tDeviation percentage from authorized ground speed. ","d":"D.\tWind speed along runway"}},{"num":421,"sample":"1K711","correct":"A","question":"What is the frequency range of an aircraft's Automatic Direction Finding (ADF) equipment? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t190 kHz to 1750 kHz. ","b":"B.\t190 MHz to 1750 MHz. ","c":"C.\t108.10 MHz to 111.95 MHz. ","d":"D.\t108.00 MHz to 117.95 MHz"}},{"num":422,"sample":"1K712","correct":"B","question":"What is meant by the term 'night effect' when using an aircraft's Automatic Direction Finding (ADF) equipment?  Night effect refers to the fact that: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAll Non Directional Beacon (NDB) transmitters are turned-off at dusk and turned-on at dawn. ","b":"B.\tNon Directional Beacon (NDB) transmissions can bounce-off the Earth's ionosphere at night and be received at almost any direction. ","c":"C.\tAn aircraft's ADF transmissions will be slowed at night due to the increased density of the Earth's atmosphere after sunset. ","d":"D.\tAn aircraft's ADF antennas usually collect dew moisture after sunset which decreases their effective reception distance from an NDB transmitter"}},{"num":423,"sample":"1K713","correct":"A","question":"What are the transmit and receive frequencies of an aircraft's mode C transponder operating in the Air Traffic Control RADAR Beacon System (ATCRBS)? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tTransmit at 1090 MHz, and receive at 1030 MHz. ","b":"B.\tTransmit at 1030 kHz, and receive at 1090 kHz. ","c":"C.\tTransmit at 1090 kHz, and receive at 1030 kHz. ","d":"D.\tTransmit at 1030 MHz, and receive at 1090 MHz"}},{"num":424,"sample":"1K714","correct":"C","question":"In addition to duplicating the functions of a mode C transponder, an aircraft's mode S transponder can also provide: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tPrimary RADAR surveillance capabilities. ","b":"B.\tLong range lightning detection. ","c":"C.\tMid-Air collision avoidance capabilities. ","d":"D.\tBackup VHF voice communication abilities"}},{"num":425,"sample":"1K715","correct":"B","question":"What type of encoding is used in an aircraft's mode C transponder transmission to a ground station of the Air Traffic Control RADAR Beacon System (ATCRBS)? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tDifferential phase shift keying. ","b":"B.\tPulse position modulation. ","c":"C.\tDoppler effect compressional encryption. ","d":"D.\tAmplitude modulation at 95%"}},{"num":426,"sample":"1K716","correct":"D","question":"Choose the only correct statement about an aircraft's Automatic Direction Finding (ADF) equipment. ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAn aircraft's ADF transmission exhibits primarily a line-of-sight range to the ground-based target station and will not follow the curvature of the Earth. ","b":"B.\tOnly a single omnidirectional sense antenna is required to receive an NDB transmission and process the signal to calculate the aircraft's bearing to the selected ground station. ","c":"C.\tAll frequencies in the ADF's operating range except the commercial standard broadcast stations (550 to 1660 kHz) can be utilized as a navigational Non Directional Beacon (NDB) signal. ","d":"D.\tAn aircraft's ADF antennas can receive transmissions that are over the Earth's horizon (sometimes several hundred miles away) since these signals will follow the curvature of the Earth"}},{"num":427,"sample":"1K721","correct":"D","question":"What type of antenna pattern is radiated from a ground station phased-array directional antenna when transmitting the PPM pulses in a Mode S interrogation signal of an aircraft's Traffic alert and Collision Avoidance System (TCAS) installation? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1090 MHz directional pattern. ","b":"B.\t1030 MHz omnidirectional pattern. ","c":"C.\t1090 MHz omnidirectional pattern. ","d":"D.\t1030 MHz directional pattern"}},{"num":428,"sample":"1K722","correct":"C","question":"What type of antenna is used in an aircraft's Instrument Landing System (ILS) marker beacon installation? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAn electronically steerable phased-array antenna that radiates a directional antenna pattern. ","b":"B.\tA folded dipole reception antenna. ","c":"C.\tA balanced loop reception antenna. ","d":"D.\tA horizontally polarized antenna that radiates an omnidirectional antenna pattern"}},{"num":429,"sample":"1K723","correct":"A","question":"What is the frequency range of an aircraft's Very High Frequency (VHF) communications? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t118.000 MHz to 136.975 MHz (worldwide up to 151.975 MHz). ","b":"B.\t108.00 MHz to 117.95 MHz. ","c":"C.\t329.15 MHz to 335.00 MHz. ","d":"D.\t2.000 MHz to 29.999 MHz"}},{"num":430,"sample":"1K724","correct":"D","question":"Aircraft Emergency Locator Transmitters (ELT) operate on what frequencies? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t121.5 MHz. ","b":"B.\t243 MHz. ","c":"C.\t121.5 and 243 MHz. ","d":"D.\t121.5, 243 and 406 MHz"}},{"num":431,"sample":"1K725","correct":"C","question":"What is the frequency range of an aircraft's radio altimeter? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t962 MHz to 1213 MHz. ","b":"B.\t329.15 MHz to 335.00 MHz. ","c":"C.\t4250 MHz to 4350 MHz. ","d":"D.\t108.00 MHz to 117.95 MHz"}},{"num":432,"sample":"1K726","correct":"B","question":"What type of antenna is attached to an aircraft's Mode C transponder installation and used to receive 1030 MHz interrogation signals from the Air Traffic Control Radar Beacon System (ATCRBS)? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAn electronically steerable phased-array directional antenna. ","b":"B.\tAn L-band monopole blade-type omnidirectional antenna. ","c":"C.\tA folded dipole reception antenna. ","d":"D.\tAn internally mounted, mechanically rotatable loop antenna"}},{"num":433,"sample":"1K731","correct":"C","question":"Some aircraft and avionics equipment operates with a prime power line frequency of 400 Hz.  What is the principle advantage of a higher line frequency? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t400 Hz power supplies draw less current than 60 Hz supplies allowing more current available for other systems on the aircraft. ","b":"B.\tA 400 Hz power supply generates less heat and operates much more efficiently than a 60 Hz power supply. ","c":"C.\tThe magnetic devices in a 400 Hz power supply such as transformers, chokes and filters are smaller and lighter than those used in 60 Hz power supplies. ","d":"D.\t400 Hz power supplies are much less expensive to produce than power supplies with lower line frequencies"}},{"num":434,"sample":"1K732","correct":"A","question":"Aviation services use predominantly ____ microphones. ","answers":{"a":"A.\tDynamic. ","b":"B.\tCarbon. ","c":"C.\tCondenser. ","d":"D.\tPiezoelectric crystal"}},{"num":435,"sample":"1K733","correct":"D","question":"Typical airborne HF transmitters usually provide a nominal RF power output to the antenna of ____ watts, compared with ____ watts RF output from a typical VHF transmitter. ","answers":{"a":"A.\t10, 50. ","b":"B.\t50, 10. ","c":"C.\t20, 100. ","d":"D.\t100, 20"}},{"num":436,"sample":"1K734","correct":"A","question":"Before ground testing an aircraft RADAR, the operator should: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tEnsure that the area in front of the antenna is clear of other maintenance personnel to avoid radiation hazards. ","b":"B.\tBe sure the receiver has been properly shielded and grounded. ","c":"C.\tFirst test the transmitter connected to a matched load. ","d":"D.\tMeasure power supply voltages to prevent circuit damage"}},{"num":437,"sample":"1K735","correct":"B","question":"What type of antenna is used in an aircraft's Very High Frequency Omnidirectional Range (VOR) and Localizer (LOC) installations? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tVertically polarized antenna that radiates an omnidirectional antenna pattern. ","b":"B.\tHorizontally polarized omnidirection reception antenna. ","c":"C.\tBalanced loop transmission antenna. ","d":"D.\tFolded dipole reception antenna"}},{"num":438,"sample":"1K736","correct":"B","question":"What is the function of a commercial aircraft's SELCAL installation?  SELCAL is a type of aircraft communications __________. ","answers":{"a":"A.\tDevice that allows an aircraft's receiver to be continuously calibrated for signal selectivity. ","b":"B.\tSystem where a ground-based transmitter can call a selected aircraft or group of aircraft without the flight crew monitoring the ground-station frequency. ","c":"C.\tTransmission that uses sequential logic algorithm encryption to prevent public 'eavesdropping' of crucial aircraft flight data. ","d":"D.\tSystem where an airborne transmitter can selectively calculate the line-of-sight distance to several ground-station receivers"}},{"num":439,"sample":"1L741","correct":"B","question":"What is a 1/2 digit on a DMM? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tSmaller physical readout on the left side of the display. ","b":"B.\tPartial extended accuracy on lower part of the range. ","c":"C.\tSmaller physical readout on the right side. ","d":"D.\tDoes not apply to DMMs"}},{"num":440,"sample":"1L742","correct":"D","question":"A 50 microampere meter movement has an internal resistance of 2,000 ohms.  What applied voltage is required to indicate half-scale deflection? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t0.01 volts ","b":"B.\t0.10 volts ","c":"C.\t0.005 volts. ","d":"D.\t0.05 volts"}},{"num":441,"sample":"1L743","correct":"A","question":"What is the purpose of a series multiplier resistor used with a voltmeter? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIt is used to increase the voltage-indicating range of the voltmeter. ","b":"B.\tA multiplier resistor is not used with a voltmeter. ","c":"C.\tIt is used to decrease the voltage-indicating range of the voltmeter. ","d":"D.\tIt is used to increase the current-indicating range of an ammeter, not a voltmeter"}},{"num":442,"sample":"1L744","correct":"C","question":"What is the purpose of a shunt resistor used with an ammeter? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA shunt resistor is not used with an ammeter. ","b":"B.\tIt is used to decrease the ampere indicating range of the ammeter. ","c":"C.\tIt is used to increase the ampere indicating range of the ammeter. ","d":"D.\tIt is used to increase the voltage indicating range of the voltmeter, not the ammeter"}},{"num":443,"sample":"1L745","correct":"B","question":"What instrument is used to indicate high and low digital voltage states? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tOhmmeter. ","b":"B.\tLogic probe. ","c":"C.\tMegger. ","d":"D.\tSignal strength meter"}},{"num":444,"sample":"1L746","correct":"C","question":"What instrument may be used to verify proper radio antenna functioning? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tDigital ohm meter. ","b":"B.\tHewlett-Packard frequency meter. ","c":"C.\tAn SWR meter. ","d":"D.\tDifferent radio"}},{"num":445,"sample":"1L751","correct":"D","question":"How is a frequency counter used? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tTo provide reference points on an analog receiver dial thereby aiding in the alignment of the receiver. ","b":"B.\tTo heterodyne the frequency being measured with a known variable frequency oscillator until zero beat is achieved, thereby indicating the unknown frequency. ","c":"C.\tTo measure the deviation in an FM transmitter in order to determine the percentage of modulation. ","d":"D.\tTo measure the time between events, or the frequency, which is the reciprocal of the time"}},{"num":446,"sample":"1L752","correct":"B","question":"What is a frequency standard? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA well-known (standard) frequency used for transmitting certain messages. ","b":"B.\tA device used to produce a highly accurate reference frequency. ","c":"C.\tA device for accurately measuring frequency to within 1 Hz. ","d":"D.\tA device used to generate wide-band random frequencies"}},{"num":447,"sample":"1L753","correct":"C","question":"What equipment may be useful to track down EMI aboard a ship or aircraft? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tFluke multimeter. ","b":"B.\tAn oscilloscope. ","c":"C.\tPortable AM receiver. ","d":"D.\tA logic probe"}},{"num":448,"sample":"1L754","correct":"A","question":"On an analog wattmeter, what part of the scale is most accurate and how much does that accuracy extend to the rest of the reading scale? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe accuracy is only at full scale, and that absolute number reading is carried through to the rest of the range.  The upper 1/3 of the meter is the only truly calibrated part. ","b":"B.\tThe accuracy is constant throughout the entire range of the meter. ","c":"C.\tThe accuracy is only there at the upper 5% of the meter, and is not carried through at any other reading. ","d":"D.\tThe accuracy cannot be determined at any reading"}},{"num":449,"sample":"1L755","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following frequency standards is used as a time base standard by field technicians? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tQuartz Crystal. ","b":"B.\tRubidium Standard. ","c":"C.\tCesium Beam Standard. ","d":"D.\tLC Tank Oscillator"}},{"num":450,"sample":"1L756","correct":"A","question":"Which of the following contains a multirange AF voltmeter calibrated in dB and a sharp, internal 1000 Hz bandstop filter, both used in conjunction with each other to perform quieting tests? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tSINAD meter. ","b":"B.\tReflectometer. ","c":"C.\tDip meter. ","d":"D.\tVector-impedance meter"}},{"num":451,"sample":"1L761","correct":"B","question":"What is used to decrease circuit loading when using an oscilloscope? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tDual input amplifiers. ","b":"B.\t10:1 divider probe. ","c":"C.\tInductive probe. ","d":"D.\tResistive probe"}},{"num":452,"sample":"1L762","correct":"C","question":"How does a spectrum analyzer differ from a conventional oscilloscope? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe oscilloscope is used to display electrical signals while the spectrum analyzer is used to measure ionospheric reflection. ","b":"B.\tThe oscilloscope is used to display electrical signals in the frequency domain while the spectrum analyzer is used to display electrical signals in the time domain. ","c":"C.\tThe oscilloscope is used to display electrical signals in the time domain while the spectrum analyzer is used to display electrical signals in the frequency domain. ","d":"D.\tThe oscilloscope is used for displaying audio frequencies and the spectrum analyzer is used for displaying radio frequencies"}},{"num":453,"sample":"1L763","correct":"D","question":"What stage determines the maximum frequency response of an oscilloscope? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tTime base. ","b":"B.\tHorizontal sweep. ","c":"C.\tPower supply. ","d":"D.\tVertical amplifier"}},{"num":454,"sample":"1L764","correct":"A","question":"What factors limit the accuracy, frequency response, and stability of an oscilloscope? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tSweep oscillator quality and deflection amplifier bandwidth. ","b":"B.\tTube face voltage increments and deflection amplifier voltage. ","c":"C.\tSweep oscillator quality and tube face voltage increments. ","d":"D.\tDeflection amplifier output impedance and tube face frequency increments"}},{"num":455,"sample":"1L765","correct":"C","question":"An oscilloscope can be used to accomplish all of the following except: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tMeasure electron flow with the aid of a resistor. ","b":"B.\tMeasure phase difference between two signals. ","c":"C.\tMeasure velocity of light with the aid of a light emitting diode. ","d":"D.\tMeasure electrical voltage"}},{"num":456,"sample":"1L766","correct":"D","question":"What instrument is used to check the signal quality of a single-sideband radio transmission? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tField strength meter. ","b":"B.\tSignal level meter. ","c":"C.\tSidetone monitor. ","d":"D.\tOscilloscope"}},{"num":457,"sample":"1L771","correct":"B","question":"A(n) ____ and ____ can be combined to measure the characteristics of transmission lines.  Such an arrangement is known as a time-domain reflectometer (TDR). ","answers":{"a":"A.\tFrequency spectrum analyzer, RF generator. ","b":"B.\tOscilloscope, pulse generator. ","c":"C.\tAC millivolt meter, AF generator. ","d":"D.\tFrequency counter, linear detector"}},{"num":458,"sample":"1L772","correct":"D","question":"What does the horizontal axis of a spectrum analyzer display? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAmplitude. ","b":"B.\tVoltage. ","c":"C.\tResonance. ","d":"D.\tFrequency"}},{"num":459,"sample":"1L773","correct":"A","question":"What does the vertical axis of a spectrum analyzer display? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAmplitude. ","b":"B.\tDuration. ","c":"C.\tFrequency. ","d":"D.\tTime"}},{"num":460,"sample":"1L774","correct":"D","question":"What instrument is most accurate when checking antennas and transmission lines at the operating frequency of the antenna? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tTime domain reflectometer. ","b":"B.\tWattmeter. ","c":"C.\tDMM. ","d":"D.\tFrequency domain reflectometer"}},{"num":461,"sample":"1L775","correct":"A","question":"What test instrument can be used to display spurious signals in the output of a radio transmitter? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA spectrum analyzer. ","b":"B.\tA wattmeter. ","c":"C.\tA logic analyzer. ","d":"D.\tA time domain reflectometer"}},{"num":462,"sample":"1L776","correct":"C","question":"What instrument is commonly used by radio service technicians to monitor frequency, modulation, check receiver sensitivity, distortion, and to generate audio tones? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tOscilloscope. ","b":"B.\tSpectrum analyzer. ","c":"C.\tService monitor. ","d":"D.\tDMM"}},{"num":463,"sample":"1L781","correct":"C","question":"Can a P25 radio system be monitored with a scanner? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tYes , regardless if it has P25 decoding or not. ","b":"B.\tNo. ","c":"C.\tYes, if the scanner has P25 decoding. ","d":"D.\tYes, but it must also have P26 decoding"}},{"num":464,"sample":"1L782","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following answers is true? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe RF Power reading on a CDMA (code division multiple access) radio will be very accurate on an analog power meter. ","b":"B.\tThe RF Power reading on a CDMA radio is not accurate on an analog power meter. ","c":"C.\tPower cannot be measured using CDMA modulation. ","d":"D.\tNone of the above"}},{"num":465,"sample":"1L783","correct":"C","question":"What is a common method used to program radios without using a 'wired' connection? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBanding. ","b":"B.\tUsing the ultraviolet from a programmed radio to repeat the programming in another. ","c":"C.\tInfra-red communication. ","d":"D.\tHaving the radio maker send down a programming signal via satellite"}},{"num":466,"sample":"1L784","correct":"A","question":"What is the common method for determining the exact sensitivity specification of a receiver? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tMeasure the recovered audio for 12 dB of SINAD. ","b":"B.\tMeasure the recovered audio for 10 dB of quieting. ","c":"C.\tMeasure the recovered audio for 10 dB of SINAD. ","d":"D.\tMeasure the recovered audio for 25 dB of quieting"}},{"num":467,"sample":"1L785","correct":"D","question":"A communications technician would perform a modulation-acceptance bandwidth test in order to: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAscertain the audio frequency response of the receiver. ","b":"B.\tDetermine whether the CTCSS in the receiver is operating correctly. ","c":"C.\tVerify the results from a 12 dB SINAD test. ","d":"D.\tDetermine the effective bandwidth of a communications receiver"}},{"num":468,"sample":"1L786","correct":"B","question":"What is the maximum FM deviation for voice operation of a normal wideband channel on VHF and UHF? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t2.5 kHz. ","b":"B.\t5.0 kHz. ","c":"C.\t7.5 kHz. ","d":"D.\t10 kHz "}},{"num":469,"sample":"1L791","correct":"A","question":"When soldering or working with CMOS electronics products or equipment, a wrist strap: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tMust have less than 100,000 ohms of resistance to prevent static electricity. ","b":"B.\tCannot be used when repairing TTL devices. ","c":"C.\tMust be grounded to a water pipe. ","d":"D.\tDoes not work well in conjunction with anti-static floor mats"}},{"num":470,"sample":"1L792","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following is the preferred method of cleaning solder from plated-through circuit-board holes? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tUse a dental pick. ","b":"B.\tUse a vacuum device. ","c":"C.\tUse a soldering iron tip that has a temperature above 900 degrees F. ","d":"D.\tUse an air jet device"}},{"num":471,"sample":"1L793","correct":"D","question":"What is the proper way to cut plastic wire ties? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tWith scissors. ","b":"B.\tWith a knife. ","c":"C.\tWith semi-flush diagonal pliers. ","d":"D.\tWith flush-cut diagonal pliers and cut flush"}},{"num":472,"sample":"1L794","correct":"A","question":"The ideal method of removing insulation from wire is: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe thermal stripper. ","b":"B.\tThe pocket knife. ","c":"C.\tA mechanical wire stripper. ","d":"D.\tThe scissor action stripping tool"}},{"num":473,"sample":"1L795","correct":"B","question":"A 'hot gas bonder' is used: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tTo apply solder to the iron tip while it is heating the component. ","b":"B.\tFor non-contact melting of solder. ","c":"C.\tTo allow soldering both sides of the PC board simultaneously. ","d":"D.\tTo cure LCA adhesives"}},{"num":474,"sample":"1L796","correct":"C","question":"When repairing circuit board assemblies it is most important to: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tUse a dental pick to clear plated-through holes. ","b":"B.\tBridge broken copper traces with solder. ","c":"C.\tWear safety glasses. ","d":"D.\tUse a holding fixture"}},{"num":475,"sample":"1L801","correct":"D","question":"What color is the binder for pairs 51-75 in a 100-pair cable? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tRed. ","b":"B.\tBlue. ","c":"C.\tBlack. ","d":"D.\tGreen"}},{"num":476,"sample":"1L802","correct":"C","question":"What is most important when routing cables in a mobile unit? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThat cables be cut to the exact length. ","b":"B.\tAssuring accessibility of the radio for servicing from outside the vehicle. ","c":"C.\tAssuring radio or electronics cables do not interfere with the normal operation of the vehicle. ","d":"D.\tAssuring cables are concealed under floor mats or carpeting"}},{"num":477,"sample":"1L803","correct":"B","question":"Why should you not use white or translucent plastic tie wraps on a radio tower? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tWhite tie wraps are not FAA approved. ","b":"B.\tUV radiation from the Sun deteriorates the plastic very quickly. ","c":"C.\tThe white color attracts wasps ","d":"D.\tThe black tie wraps may cause electrolysis"}},{"num":478,"sample":"1L804","correct":"C","question":"What is the 6th pair color code in a 25 pair switchboard cable as is found in building telecommunications interconnections? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBlue/Green, Green/Blue. ","b":"B.\tRed/Blue, White/Violet. ","c":"C.\tRed/Blue, Blue/Red. ","d":"D.\tWhite/Slate, Slate/White"}},{"num":479,"sample":"1L805","correct":"D","question":"What tolerance off of plumb should a single base station radio rack be installed? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tNo tolerance allowed. ","b":"B.\tJust outside the bubble on a level. ","c":"C.\tAll the way to one end. ","d":"D.\tJust inside the bubble on a level"}},{"num":480,"sample":"1L806","correct":"A","question":"What type of wire would connect an SSB automatic tuner to an insulated backstay? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tGTO-15 high-voltage cable. ","b":"B.\tRG8U. ","c":"C.\tRG213. ","d":"D.\t16-gauge two-conductor"}},{"num":481,"sample":"1L811","correct":"A","question":"On a 150 watt marine SSB HF transceiver, what would be indicated by a steady output of 75 watts when keying the transmitter on? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThere is probably a defect in the system causing the carrier to be transmitted. ","b":"B.\tOne of the sidebands is missing. ","c":"C.\tBoth sidebands are being transmitting. ","d":"D.\tThe operation is normal"}},{"num":482,"sample":"1L812","correct":"B","question":"The tachometer of a building's elevator circuit experiences interference caused by the radio system nearby. What is a common potential 'fix' for the problem? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tReplace the tachometer of the elevator. ","b":"B.\tAdd a .01 &mu;F capacitor across the motor/tachometer leads. ","c":"C.\tAdd a 200 &mu;F capacity across the motor/tachometer leads. ","d":"D.\tAdd an isolating resistor in series with the motor leads"}},{"num":483,"sample":"1L813","correct":"A","question":"A common method of programming portable or mobile radios is to use a: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA laptop computer. ","b":"B.\tDummy load. ","c":"C.\tA wattmeter. ","d":"D.\tA signal generator"}},{"num":484,"sample":"1L814","correct":"C","question":"In a software-defined transceiver, what would be the best way for a technician to make a quick overall evaluation of the radio's operational condition? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tSet up a spectrum analyzer and service monitor and manually verify the manufacturer's specifications. ","b":"B.\tUse another radio on the same frequency to check the transmitter. ","c":"C.\tUse the built-in self-test feature. ","d":"D.\tUsing on-board self-test routines are strictly prohibited by the FCC in commercial transmitters"}},{"num":485,"sample":"1L815","correct":"B","question":"How might an installer verify correct GPS sentence to marine DSC VHF radio? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tPress and hold the red distress button. ","b":"B.\tLook for latitude and longitude on the display. ","c":"C.\tLook for GPS confirmation readout. ","d":"D.\tAsk for VHF radio check position report"}},{"num":486,"sample":"1L816","correct":"D","question":"What steps must be taken to activate the DSC emergency signaling function on a marine VHF? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tSeparate 12 volts to the switch. ","b":"B.\tSecondary DSC transmit antenna. ","c":"C.\tGPS position input. ","d":"D.\tInput of registered 9-digit MMSI"}},{"num":487,"sample":"1M821","correct":"D","question":"What term describes a wide-bandwidth communications system in which the RF carrier frequency varies according to some predetermined sequence? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAmplitude compandored single sideband. ","b":"B.\tSITOR. ","c":"C.\tTime-domain frequency modulation. ","d":"D.\tSpread spectrum communication"}},{"num":488,"sample":"1M822","correct":"C","question":"Name two types of spread spectrum systems used in most RF communications applications? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAM and FM. ","b":"B.\tQPSK or QAM. ","c":"C.\tDirect Sequence and Frequency Hopping. ","d":"D.\tFrequency Hopping and APSK"}},{"num":489,"sample":"1M823","correct":"A","question":"What is the term used to describe a spread spectrum communications system where the center frequency of a conventional carrier is altered many times per second in accordance with a pseudo-random list of channels? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tFrequency hopping. ","b":"B.\tDirect sequence. ","c":"C.\tTime-domain frequency modulation. ","d":"D.\tFrequency compandored spread spectrum"}},{"num":490,"sample":"1M824","correct":"D","question":"A TDMA radio uses what to carry the multiple conversations sequentially? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tSeparate frequencies. ","b":"B.\tSeparate pilot tones. ","c":"C.\tSeparate power levels. ","d":"D.\tSeparate time slots"}},{"num":491,"sample":"1M825","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following statements about SSB voice transmissions is correct? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThey use A3E emission which are produced by modulating the final amplifier. ","b":"B.\tThey use F3E emission which is produced by phase shifting the carrier. ","c":"C.\tThey normally use J3E emissions, which consists of one sideband and a suppressed carrier. ","d":"D.\tThey may use A1A emission to suppress the carrier"}},{"num":492,"sample":"1M826","correct":"B","question":"What are the two most-used PCS (Personal Communications Systems) coding techniques used to separate different calls? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tQPSK and QAM. ","b":"B.\tCDMA and GSM. ","c":"C.\tABCD and SYZ. ","d":"D.\tAM and Frequency Hopping"}},{"num":493,"sample":"1M831","correct":"C","question":"What is a CODEC? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA device to read Morse code. ","b":"B.\tA computer operated digital encoding compandor. ","c":"C.\tA coder/decoder IC or circuitry that converts a voice signal into a predetermined digital format for encrypted transmission. ","d":"D.\tA voice amplitude compression chip"}},{"num":494,"sample":"1M832","correct":"A","question":"The GSM (Global System for Mobile Communications) uses what type of CODEC for digital mobile radio system communications? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tRegular-Pulse Excited (RPE). ","b":"B.\tCode-Excited Linear Predictive (CLEP). ","c":"C.\tMulti-Pulse Excited (MPE). ","d":"D.\tLinear Excited Code (LEC)"}},{"num":495,"sample":"1M833","correct":"D","question":"Which of the following codes has gained the widest acceptance for exchange of data from one computer to another? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tGray. ","b":"B.\tBaudot. ","c":"C.\tMorse. ","d":"D.\tASCII"}},{"num":496,"sample":"1M834","correct":"A","question":"The International Organization for Standardization has developed a seven-level reference model for a packet-radio communications structure.  What level is responsible for the actual transmission of data and handshaking signals? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe physical layer. ","b":"B.\tThe transport layer. ","c":"C.\tThe communications layer. ","d":"D.\tThe synchronization layer"}},{"num":497,"sample":"1M835","correct":"D","question":"What CODEC is used in Phase 2 P25 radios? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIWCE. ","b":"B.\tIMBC. ","c":"C.\tIMMM. ","d":"D.\tAMBE"}},{"num":498,"sample":"1M836","correct":"B","question":"The International Organization for Standardization has developed a seven-level reference model for a packet-radio communications structure. The _______ level arranges the bits into frames and controls data flow. ","answers":{"a":"A.\tTransport layer. ","b":"B.\tLink layer. ","c":"C.\tCommunications layer. ","d":"D.\tSynchronization layer"}},{"num":499,"sample":"1M841","correct":"B","question":"What is a SDR? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tSoftware Deviation Ratio. ","b":"B.\tSoftware Defined Radio. ","c":"C.\tSWR Meter. ","d":"D.\tStatic Dynamic Ram"}},{"num":500,"sample":"1M842","correct":"D","question":"What does the DSP not do in a modern DSP radio? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tControl frequency. ","b":"B.\tControl modulation. ","c":"C.\tControl detection. ","d":"D.\tControl SWR"}},{"num":501,"sample":"1M843","correct":"A","question":"Which statement best describes the code used for GMDSS-DSC transmissions? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA 10 bit error correcting code starting with bits of data followed by a 3 bit error correcting code. ","b":"B.\tA 10 bit error correcting code starting with a 3 bit error correcting code followed by 7 bits of data. ","c":"C.\tAn 8 bit code with 7 bits of data followed by a single parity bit. ","d":"D.\tA 7 bit code that is transmitted twice for error correction"}},{"num":502,"sample":"1M844","correct":"C","question":"Which is the code used for SITOR-A and -B transmissions? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe 5 bit baudot telex code. ","b":"B.\tEach character consists of 7 bits with 3 'zeros' and 4 'ones'. ","c":"C.\tEach character consists of 7 bits with 4 'zeros' and 3 'ones'. ","d":"D.\tEach character has 7 bits of data and 3 bits for error correction"}},{"num":503,"sample":"1M845","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following statements is true? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe Signal Repetition character (1001100) is used as a control signal in SITOR-ARQ. ","b":"B.\tThe Idle Signal (a) (0000111) is used for FEC Phasing Signal 1. ","c":"C.\tThe Idle Signal (b) (0011001) is used for FEC Phasing Signal 2. ","d":"D.\tThe Control Signal 1 (0101100) is used to determine the time displacement in SITOR-B"}},{"num":504,"sample":"1M846","correct":"C","question":"What principle allows multiple conversations to be able to share one radio channel on a GSM channel? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tFrequency Division Multiplex. ","b":"B.\tDouble sideband. ","c":"C.\tTime Division Multiplex. ","d":"D.\tNone of the above"}},{"num":505,"sample":"1N851","correct":"D","question":"What is the channel spacing used for VHF marine radio? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t10 kHz. ","b":"B.\t12.5 kHz. ","c":"C.\t20 kHz. ","d":"D.\t25 kHz"}},{"num":506,"sample":"1N852","correct":"B","question":"What VHF channel is assigned for distress and calling? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t70. ","b":"B.\t16. ","c":"C.\t21A. ","d":"D.\t68"}},{"num":507,"sample":"1N853","correct":"C","question":"What VHF Channel is used for Digital Selective Calling and acknowledgement? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t16. ","b":"B.\t21A. ","c":"C.\t70. ","d":"D.\t68"}},{"num":508,"sample":"1N854","correct":"A","question":"Maximum allowable frequency deviation for VHF marine radios is: ","answers":{"a":"A.\t+/- 5 kHz. ","b":"B.\t+/- 15 kHz. ","c":"C.\t+/- 2.5 kHz. ","d":"D.\t+/- 25 kHz"}},{"num":509,"sample":"1N855","correct":"B","question":"What is the reason for the USA-INT control or function? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIt changes channels that are normally simplex channels into duplex channels. ","b":"B.\tIt changes some channels that are normally duplex channels into simplex channels. ","c":"C.\tWhen the control is set to 'INT' the range is increased. ","d":"D.\tNone of the above"}},{"num":510,"sample":"1N856","correct":"A","question":"How might an installer verify correct GPS sentence to marine DSC VHF radio? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tLook for latitude and longitude, plus speed, on VHF display. ","b":"B.\tPress and hold the red distress button. ","c":"C.\tLook for GPS confirmation readout. ","d":"D.\tAsk for VHF radio check position report"}},{"num":511,"sample":"1N861","correct":"B","question":"What is a common occurrence when voice-testing an SSB aboard a boat? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAmmeter fluctuates down with each spoken word. ","b":"B.\tVoltage panel indicator lamps may glow with each syllable. ","c":"C.\tAutomatic tuner cycles on each syllable. ","d":"D.\tMinimal voltage drop seen at power source"}},{"num":512,"sample":"1N862","correct":"C","question":"What might contribute to apparent low voltage on marine SSB transmitting? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBlown red fuse. ","b":"B.\tToo much grounding. ","c":"C.\tBlown black negative fuse. ","d":"D.\tAntenna mismatch"}},{"num":513,"sample":"1N863","correct":"D","question":"What type of wire connects an SSB automatic tuner to an insulated backstay? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tRG8U. ","b":"B.\tRG213. ","c":"C.\t16-gauge two-conductor. ","d":"D.\tGTO-15 high-voltage cable"}},{"num":514,"sample":"1N864","correct":"A","question":"Which of the following statements concerning SITOR communications is true? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tARQ message transmissions are made in data groups consisting of three-character blocks. ","b":"B.\tARQ transmissions are acknowledged by the Information Receiving Station only at the end of the message. ","c":"C.\tARQ communications rely upon error correction by time diversity transmission and reception. ","d":"D.\tForward error correction is an interactive mode"}},{"num":515,"sample":"1N865","correct":"C","question":"The sequence ARQ, FEC, SFEC best corresponds to which of the following sequences? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tOne-way communications to a single station, one-way communications to all stations, two-way communications. ","b":"B.\tOne-way communications to all stations, two-way communications, one-way communications to a single station. ","c":"C.\tTwo way communications, one-way communications to all stations, one-way communications to a single station. ","d":"D.\tTwo way communications, one-way communications to a single station, one-way communications to all stations"}},{"num":516,"sample":"1N866","correct":"D","question":"Which of the following statements concerning SITOR communications is true? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tCommunication is established on the working channel and answerbacks are exchanged before FEC broadcasts can be received. ","b":"B.\tIn the ARQ mode each character is transmitted twice. ","c":"C.\tWeather broadcasts cannot be made in FEC because sending each character twice would cause the broadcast to be prohibitively long. ","d":"D.\tTwo-way communication with the coast radio station using FEC is not necessary to be able to receive the broadcasts"}},{"num":517,"sample":"1N871","correct":"B","question":"What causes the SART to begin a transmission? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tWhen activated manually, it begins radiating immediately. ","b":"B.\tAfter being activated the SART responds to RADAR interrogation. ","c":"C.\tIt is either manually or water activated before radiating. ","d":"D.\tIt begins radiating only when keyed by the operator"}},{"num":518,"sample":"1N872","correct":"D","question":"How should the signal from a Search And Rescue RADAR Transponder appear on a RADAR display? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tA series of dashes. ","b":"B.\tA series of spirals all originating from the range and bearing of the SART. ","c":"C.\tA series of twenty dashes. ","d":"D.\tA series of 12 equally spaced dots"}},{"num":519,"sample":"1N873","correct":"A","question":"In which frequency band does a search and rescue transponder operate? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t9 GHz. ","b":"B.\t3 GHz. ","c":"C.\tS-band. ","d":"D.\t406 MHz"}},{"num":520,"sample":"1N874","correct":"D","question":"Which piece of required GMDSS equipment is the primary source of transmitting locating signals? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tRadio Direction Finder (RDF). ","b":"B.\tA SART transmitting on 406 MHz. ","c":"C.\tSurvival Craft Transceiver. ","d":"D.\tAn EPIRB transmitting on 406 MHz"}},{"num":521,"sample":"1N875","correct":"A","question":"Which of the following statements concerning satellite EPIRBs is true? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tOnce activated, these EPIRBs transmit a signal for use in identifying the vessel and for determining the position of the beacon. ","b":"B.\tThe coded signal identifies the nature of the distress situation. ","c":"C.\tThe coded signal only identifies the vessel's name and port of registry. ","d":"D.\tIf the GMDSS Radio Operator does not program the EPIRB, it will transmit default information such as the follow-on communications frequency and mode"}},{"num":522,"sample":"1N876","correct":"C","question":"What statement is true regarding 406 MHz EPIRB transmissions? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAllows immediate voice communications with the RCC. ","b":"B.\tCoding permits the SAR authorities to know if manually or automatically activated. ","c":"C.\tTransmits a unique hexadecimal identification number. ","d":"D.\tRadio Operator programs an I.D"}},{"num":523,"sample":"1N881","correct":"C","question":"What is facsimile? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe transmission of still pictures by slow-scan television. ","b":"B.\tThe transmission of characters by radioteletype that form a picture when printed. ","c":"C.\tThe transmission of printed pictures for permanent display on paper. ","d":"D.\tThe transmission of video by television"}},{"num":524,"sample":"1N882","correct":"B","question":"What is the standard scan rate for high-frequency 3 MHz - 23 MHz weather facsimile reception from shore stations? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t240 lines per minute. ","b":"B.\t120 lines per minute. ","c":"C.\t150 lines per second. ","d":"D.\t60 lines per second"}},{"num":525,"sample":"1N883","correct":"C","question":"What would be the bandwidth of a good crystal lattice band-pass filter for weather facsimile HF (high frequency) reception? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t500 Hz at -6 dB. ","b":"B.\t6 kHz at -6 dB. ","c":"C.\t1 kHz at -6 dB. ","d":"D.\t15 kHz at -6 dB"}},{"num":526,"sample":"1N884","correct":"A","question":"Which of the following statements about NAVTEX is true? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tReceives MSI broadcasts using SITOR-B or FEC mode. ","b":"B.\tThe ship station transmits on 518 kHz. ","c":"C.\tThe ship receives MSI broadcasts using SITOR-A or ARQ mode. ","d":"D.\tNAVTEX is received on 2182 kHz using SSB"}},{"num":527,"sample":"1N885","correct":"D","question":"Which of the following is the primary frequency that is used exclusively for NAVTEX broadcasts internationally? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t2187.5 kHz. ","b":"B.\t4209.5 kHz. ","c":"C.\tVHF channel 16. ","d":"D.\t518 kHz"}},{"num":528,"sample":"1N886","correct":"B","question":"What determines whether a NAVTEX receiver does not print a particular type of message content? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe message does not concern your vessel. ","b":"B.\tThe subject indicator matches that programmed for rejection by the operator. ","c":"C.\tThe transmitting station ID covering your area has not been programmed for rejection by the operator. ","d":"D.\tAll messages sent during each broadcast are printed"}},{"num":529,"sample":"1N891","correct":"A","question":"What data language is bi-directional, multi-transmitter, multi-receiver network? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tNMEA 2000. ","b":"B.\tNMEA 0181. ","c":"C.\tNMEA 0182. ","d":"D.\tNMEA 0183"}},{"num":530,"sample":"1N892","correct":"B","question":"How should shielding be grounded on an NMEA 0183 data line? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tUnterminated at both ends. ","b":"B.\tTerminated to ground at the talker and unterminated at the listener. ","c":"C.\tUnterminated at the talker and terminated at the listener. ","d":"D.\tTerminated at both the talker and listener"}},{"num":531,"sample":"1N893","correct":"D","question":"What might occur in NMEA 2000 network topology if one device in line should fail? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThe system shuts down until the device is removed. ","b":"B.\tOther electronics after the failed device will be inoperable. ","c":"C.\tThe main fuse on the backbone may open. ","d":"D.\tThere will be no interruption to all other devices"}},{"num":532,"sample":"1N894","correct":"A","question":"In an NMEA 2000 device, a load equivalence number (LEN) of 1 is equivalent to how much current consumption? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t50 mA. ","b":"B.\t10 mA. ","c":"C.\t25 mA. ","d":"D.\t5 mA"}},{"num":533,"sample":"1N895","correct":"B","question":"An NMEA 2000 system with devices in a single location may be powered using this method: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tDual mid-powered network. ","b":"B.\tEnd-powered network. ","c":"C.\tIndividual devices individually powered. ","d":"D.\tNo 12 volts needed for NMEA 2000 devices"}},{"num":534,"sample":"1N896","correct":"C","question":"What voltage drop at the end of the last segment will satisfy NMEA 2000 network cabling plans? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t0.5 volts. ","b":"B.\t2.0 volts. ","c":"C.\t1.5 volts. ","d":"D.\t3.0 volts"}},{"num":535,"sample":"1O901","correct":"D","question":"What is the normal range of pulse repetition rates? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t2,000 to 4,000 pps. ","b":"B.\t1,000 to 3,000 pps. ","c":"C.\t500 to 1,000 pps. ","d":"D.\t500 to 2,000 pps"}},{"num":536,"sample":"1O902","correct":"C","question":"The RADAR range in nautical miles to an object can be found by measuring the elapsed time during a RADAR pulse and dividing this quantity by: ","answers":{"a":"A.\t0.87 seconds. ","b":"B.\t1.15 &mu;s. ","c":"C.\t12.346 &mu;s. ","d":"D.\t1.073 &mu;s"}},{"num":537,"sample":"1O903","correct":"B","question":"What is the normal range of pulse widths? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t.05 &mu;s to 0.1 &mu;s. ","b":"B.\t.05 &mu;s to 1.0 &mu;s. ","c":"C.\t1.0 &mu;s to 3.5 &mu;s. ","d":"D.\t2.5 &mu;s to 5.0 &mu;s"}},{"num":538,"sample":"1O904","correct":"C","question":"Shipboard RADAR is most commonly operated in what band? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tVHF. ","b":"B.\tUHF. ","c":"C.\tSHF. ","d":"D.\tEHF"}},{"num":539,"sample":"1O905","correct":"D","question":"The pulse repetition rate (prr) of a RADAR refers to the: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tReciprocal of the duty cycle. ","b":"B.\tPulse rate of the local oscillator. ","c":"C.\tPulse rate of the klystron. ","d":"D.\tPulse rate of the magnetron"}},{"num":540,"sample":"1O906","correct":"A","question":"If the elapsed time for a RADAR echo is 62 microseconds, what is the distance in nautical miles to the object? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t5 nautical miles. ","b":"B.\t87 nautical miles. ","c":"C.\t37 nautical miles. ","d":"D.\t11.5 nautical miles"}},{"num":541,"sample":"1O911","correct":"A","question":"The ATR box: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tPrevents the received signal from entering the transmitter. ","b":"B.\tProtects the receiver from strong RADAR signals. ","c":"C.\tTurns off the receiver when the transmitter is on. ","d":"D.\tAll of the above"}},{"num":542,"sample":"1O912","correct":"B","question":"What is the purpose or function of the RADAR duplexer/circulator? It is a/an: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tCoupling device that is used in the transition from a rectangular waveguide to a circular waveguide. ","b":"B.\tElectronic switch that allows the use of one antenna for both transmission and reception. ","c":"C.\tModified length of waveguide that is used to sample a portion of the transmitted energy for testing purposes. ","d":"D.\tDual section coupling device that allows the use of a magnetron as a transmitter"}},{"num":543,"sample":"1O913","correct":"A","question":"What device can be used to determine the performance of a RADAR system at sea? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tEcho box. ","b":"B.\tKlystron. ","c":"C.\tCirculator. ","d":"D.\tDigital signal processor"}},{"num":544,"sample":"1O914","correct":"C","question":"What is the purpose of a synchro transmitter and receiver? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tSynchronizes the transmitted and received pulse trains. ","b":"B.\tPrevents the receiver from operating during the period of the transmitted pulse. ","c":"C.\tTransmits the angular position of the antenna to the indicator unit. ","d":"D.\tKeeps the speed of the motor generator constant"}},{"num":545,"sample":"1O915","correct":"B","question":"Digital signal processing (DSP) of RADAR signals (compared with analog) causes: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tImproved display graphics. ","b":"B.\tImproved weak signal or target enhancement. ","c":"C.\tLess interference with SONAR systems. ","d":"D.\tLess interference with other radio communications equipment"}},{"num":546,"sample":"1O916","correct":"D","question":"The component or circuit providing the transmitter output power for a RADAR system is the: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThyratron. ","b":"B.\tSCR. ","c":"C.\tKlystron. ","d":"D.\tMagnetron"}},{"num":547,"sample":"1O921","correct":"D","question":"When a RADAR is being operated on the 48 mile range setting, what is the most appropriate pulse width (PW) and pulse repetition rate (pps)? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1.0 &mu;s PW and 2,000 pps. ","b":"B.\t0.05 &mu;s PW and 2,000 pps. ","c":"C.\t2.5 &mu;s PW and 2,500 pps. ","d":"D.\t1.0 &mu;s PW and 500 pps"}},{"num":548,"sample":"1O922","correct":"C","question":"When a RADAR is being operated on the 6 mile range setting what is the most appropriate pulse width and pulse repetition rate? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1.0 &mu;s PW and 500 pps. ","b":"B.\t2.0 &mu;s PW and 3,000 pps. ","c":"C.\t0.25 &mu;s PW and 1,000 pps. ","d":"D.\t0.01 &mu;s PW and 500 pps"}},{"num":549,"sample":"1O923","correct":"A","question":"We are looking at a target 25 miles away.  When a RADAR is being operated on the 25 mile range setting what is the most appropriate pulse width and pulse repetition rate? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1.0 &mu;s PW and 500 pps. ","b":"B.\t0.25 &mu;s PW and 1,000 pps. ","c":"C.\t0.01 &mu;s PW and 500 pps. ","d":"D.\t0.05 &mu;s PW and 2,000 pps"}},{"num":550,"sample":"1O924","correct":"D","question":"What pulse width and repetition rate should you use at long ranges? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tNarrow pulse width and slow repetition rate. ","b":"B.\tNarrow pulse width and fast repetition rate. ","c":"C.\tWide pulse width and fast repetition rate. ","d":"D.\tWide pulse width and slow repetition rate"}},{"num":551,"sample":"1O925","correct":"C","question":"What pulse width and repetition rate should you use at short ranges? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tWide pulse width and fast repetition rate. ","b":"B.\tNarrow pulse width and slow repetition rate. ","c":"C.\tNarrow pulse width and fast repetition rates. ","d":"D.\tWide pulse width and slow repetition rates"}},{"num":552,"sample":"1O926","correct":"B","question":"When a RADAR is being operated on the 1.5 mile range setting, what is the most appropriate pulse width and pulse repetition rate? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t0.25 &mu;s PW and 1,000 pps. ","b":"B.\t0.05 &mu;s PW and 2,000 pps. ","c":"C.\t1.0 &mu;s PW and 500 pps. ","d":"D.\t2.5 &mu;s PW and 2,500 pps"}},{"num":553,"sample":"1O931","correct":"C","question":"How does the gain of a parabolic dish antenna change when the operating frequency is doubled? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tGain does not change. ","b":"B.\tGain is multiplied by 0.707. ","c":"C.\tGain increases 6 dB. ","d":"D.\tGain increases 3 dB"}},{"num":554,"sample":"1O932","correct":"A","question":"What type of antenna or pickup device is used to extract the RADAR signal from the wave guide? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tJ-hook. ","b":"B.\tK-hook. ","c":"C.\tFolded dipole. ","d":"D.\tCirculator"}},{"num":555,"sample":"1O933","correct":"D","question":"What happens to the beamwidth of an antenna as the gain is increased? The beamwidth: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIncreases geometrically as the gain is increased. ","b":"B.\tIncreases arithmetically as the gain is increased. ","c":"C.\tIs essentially unaffected by the gain of the antenna. ","d":"D.\tDecreases as the gain is increased"}},{"num":556,"sample":"1O934","correct":"A","question":"A common shipboard RADAR antenna is the: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tSlotted array. ","b":"B.\tDipole. ","c":"C.\tStacked Yagi. ","d":"D.\tVertical Marconi"}},{"num":557,"sample":"1O935","correct":"D","question":"Conductance takes place in a waveguide: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBy interelectron delay. ","b":"B.\tThrough electrostatic field reluctance. ","c":"C.\tIn the same manner as a transmission line. ","d":"D.\tThrough electromagnetic and electrostatic fields in the walls of the waveguide"}},{"num":558,"sample":"1O936","correct":"B","question":"To couple energy into and out of a waveguide use: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tWide copper sheeting. ","b":"B.\tA thin piece of wire as an antenna. ","c":"C.\tAn LC circuit. ","d":"D.\tCapacitive coupling"}},{"num":559,"sample":"1O941","correct":"B","question":"The permanent magnetic field that surrounds a traveling-wave tube (TWT) is intended to: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tProvide a means of coupling. ","b":"B.\tPrevent the electron beam from spreading. ","c":"C.\tPrevent oscillations. ","d":"D.\tPrevent spurious oscillations"}},{"num":560,"sample":"1O942","correct":"D","question":"Prior to testing any RADAR system, the operator should first: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tCheck the system grounds. ","b":"B.\tAssure the display unit is operating normally. ","c":"C.\tInform the airport control tower or ship's master. ","d":"D.\tAssure no personnel are in front of the antenna"}},{"num":561,"sample":"1O943","correct":"A","question":"In the term 'ARPA RADAR,' ARPA is the acronym for which of the following? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAutomatic RADAR Plotting Aid. ","b":"B.\tAutomatic RADAR Positioning Angle. ","c":"C.\tAmerican RADAR Programmers Association. ","d":"D.\tAuthorized RADAR Programmer and Administrator"}},{"num":562,"sample":"1O944","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following is NOT a precaution that should be taken to ensure the magnetron is not weakened: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tKeep metal tools away from the magnet. ","b":"B.\tDo not subject it to excessive heat. ","c":"C.\tKeep the TR properly tuned. ","d":"D.\tDo not subject it to shocks and blows"}},{"num":563,"sample":"1O945","correct":"B","question":"Exposure to microwave energy from RADAR or other electronics devices is limited by U.S. Health Department regulations to _______ mW/centimeter. ","answers":{"a":"A.\t0.005. ","b":"B.\t5.0. ","c":"C.\t0.05. ","d":"D.\t0.5"}},{"num":564,"sample":"1O946","correct":"C","question":"RADAR collision avoidance systems utilize inputs from each of the following except your ship's: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tGyrocompass. ","b":"B.\tNavigation position receiver. ","c":"C.\tAnemometer. ","d":"D.\tSpeed indicator"}},{"num":565,"sample":"1P951","correct":"D","question":"What is the orbiting altitude of the Iridium satellite communications system? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t22,184 miles. ","b":"B.\t11,492 miles. ","c":"C.\t4,686 miles. ","d":"D.\t485 miles"}},{"num":566,"sample":"1P952","correct":"B","question":"What frequency band is used by the Iridium system for telephone and messaging? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t965 - 985 MHz. ","b":"B.\t1616 -1626 MHz. ","c":"C.\t1855 -1895 MHz. ","d":"D.\t2415 - 2435 MHz"}},{"num":567,"sample":"1P953","correct":"C","question":"What services are provided by the Iridium system? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAnalog voice and Data at 4.8 kbps. ","b":"B.\tDigital voice and Data at 9.6 kbps. ","c":"C.\tDigital voice and Data at 2.4 kbps. ","d":"D.\tAnalog voice and Data at 9.6 kbps"}},{"num":568,"sample":"1P954","correct":"A","question":"Which of the following statements about the Iridium system is true? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThere are 48 spot beams per satellite with a footprint of 30 miles in diameter. ","b":"B.\tThere are 48 satellites in orbit in 4 orbital planes. ","c":"C.\tThe inclination of the orbital planes is 55 degrees. ","d":"D.\tThe orbital period is approximately 85 minutes"}},{"num":569,"sample":"1P955","correct":"B","question":"What is the main function of the COSPAS-SARSAT satellite system? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tMonitor 121.5 MHz for voice distress calls. ","b":"B.\tMonitor 406 MHz for distress calls from EPIRBs. ","c":"C.\tMonitor 1635 MHz for coded distress calls. ","d":"D.\tMonitor 2197.5 kHz for hexadecimal coded DSC distress messages"}},{"num":570,"sample":"1P956","correct":"A","question":"How does the COSPAS-SARSAT satellite system determine the position of a ship in distress? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tBy measuring the Doppler shift of the 406 MHz signal taken at several different points in its orbit. ","b":"B.\tThe EPIRB always transmits its position which is relayed by the satellite to the Local User Terminal. ","c":"C.\tIt takes two different satellites to establish an accurate position. ","d":"D.\tNone of the above"}},{"num":571,"sample":"1P961","correct":"B","question":"What is the orbital altitude of INMARSAT Satellites? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t16, 436 miles. ","b":"B.\t22,177 miles. ","c":"C.\t10, 450 miles. ","d":"D.\t26,435 miles"}},{"num":572,"sample":"1P962","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following describes the INMARSAT Satellite system? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAOR at 35&deg; W, POR-E at 165&deg; W, POR-W at 155&deg; E and IOR at 56.5&deg; E. ","b":"B.\tAOR-E at 25&deg; W, AOR-W at 85&deg; W, POR at 175&deg; W and IOR at 56.5&deg; E. ","c":"C.\tAOR-E at 15.5&deg; W, AOR-W at 54&deg; W, POR at 178&deg; E and IOR at 64.5&deg; E. ","d":"D.\tAOR at 40&deg; W, POR at 178&deg; W, IOR-E at 109&deg; E and IOR-W at 46&deg; E"}},{"num":573,"sample":"1P963","correct":"D","question":"What are the directional characteristics of the INMARSAT-C SES antenna? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tHighly directional parabolic antenna requiring stabilization. ","b":"B.\tWide beam width in a cardioid pattern off the front of the antenna. ","c":"C.\tVery narrow beam width straight-up from the top of the antenna. ","d":"D.\tOmnidirectional"}},{"num":574,"sample":"1P964","correct":"A","question":"When engaging in voice communications via an INMARSAT-B terminal, what techniques are used? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tCODECs are used to digitize the voice signal. ","b":"B.\tNoise-blanking must be selected by the operator. ","c":"C.\tThe voice signal must be compressed to fit into the allowed bandwidth. ","d":"D.\tThe voice signal will be expanded at the receiving terminal"}},{"num":575,"sample":"1P965","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following statements concerning INMARSAT geostationary satellites is true? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThey are in a polar orbit, in order to provide true global coverage. ","b":"B.\tThey are in an equatorial orbit, in order to provide true global coverage. ","c":"C.\tThey provide coverage to vessels in nearly all of the world's navigable waters. ","d":"D.\tVessels sailing in equatorial waters are able to use only one satellite, whereas other vessels are able to choose between at least two satellites"}},{"num":576,"sample":"1P966","correct":"D","question":"Which of the following conditions can render INMARSAT -B communications impossible? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAn obstruction, such as a mast, causing disruption of the signal between the satellite and the SES antenna when the vessel is steering a certain course. ","b":"B.\tA satellite whose signal is on a low elevation, below the horizon. ","c":"C.\tTravel beyond the effective radius of the satellite. ","d":"D.\tAll of these"}},{"num":577,"sample":"1P971","correct":"B","question":"What is the best description for the INMARSAT-C system? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tIt provides slow speed telex and voice service. ","b":"B.\tIt is a store-and-forward system that provides routine and distress communications. ","c":"C.\tIt is a real-time telex system. ","d":"D.\tIt provides world-wide coverage"}},{"num":578,"sample":"1P972","correct":"D","question":"The INMARSAT mini-M system is a: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tMarine SONAR system. ","b":"B.\tMarine global satellite system. ","c":"C.\tMarine depth finder. ","d":"D.\tSatellite system utilizing spot beams to provide for small craft communications"}},{"num":579,"sample":"1P973","correct":"A","question":"What statement best describes the INMARSAT-B services? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tVoice at 16 kbps, Fax at 14.4 kbps and high-speed Data at 64/54. ","b":"B.\tStore and forward high speed data at 36/48 kbps. ","c":"C.\tVoice at 3 kHz, Fax at 9.6 kbps and Data at 4.8 kbps. ","d":"D.\tService is available only in areas served by highly directional spot beam antennas"}},{"num":580,"sample":"1P974","correct":"D","question":"Which INMARSAT systems offer High Speed Data at 64/54 kbps? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tC. ","b":"B.\tB and C. ","c":"C.\tMini-M. ","d":"D.\tB, M4 and Fleet"}},{"num":581,"sample":"1P975","correct":"A","question":"When INMARSAT-B and INMARSAT-C terminals are compared: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tINMARSAT-C antennas are small and omni-directional, while INMARSAT-B antennas are larger and directional. ","b":"B.\tINMARSAT-B antennas are bulkier but omni-directional, while INMARSAT-C antennas are smaller and parabolic, for aiming at the satellite. ","c":"C.\tINMARSAT-B antennas are parabolic and smaller for higher gain, while INMARSAT-C antennas are larger but omni-directional. ","d":"D.\tINMARSAT-C antennas are smaller but omni-directional, while INMARSAT-B antennas are parabolic for lower gain"}},{"num":582,"sample":"1P976","correct":"C","question":"What services are provided by the INMARSAT-M service? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tData and Fax at 4.8 kbps plus e-mail. ","b":"B.\tVoice at 3 kHz, Fax at 9.6 kbps and Data at 4.8 kbps. ","c":"C.\tVoice at 6.2 kbps, Data at 2.4 kbps, Fax at 2.4 kbps and e-mail. ","d":"D.\tData at 4.8 kbps and Fax at 9.6 kbps plus e-mail"}},{"num":583,"sample":"1P981","correct":"C","question":"Global Positioning Service (GPS) satellite orbiting altitude is: ","answers":{"a":"A.\t4,686 miles. ","b":"B.\t24,184 miles. ","c":"C.\t12,554 miles. ","d":"D.\t247 miles"}},{"num":584,"sample":"1P982","correct":"B","question":"The GPS transmitted frequencies are: ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1626.5 MHz and 1644.5 MHz. ","b":"B.\t1227.6 MHz and 1575.4 MHz. ","c":"C.\t2245.4 and 2635.4 MHz. ","d":"D.\t946.2 MHz and 1226.6 MHz"}},{"num":585,"sample":"1P983","correct":"C","question":"How many GPS satellites are normally in operation? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t8. ","b":"B.\t18. ","c":"C.\t24. ","d":"D.\t36"}},{"num":586,"sample":"1P984","correct":"A","question":"What best describes the GPS Satellites orbits? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tThey are in six orbital planes equally spaced and inclined about 55 degrees to the equator. ","b":"B.\tThey are in four orbital planes spaced 90 degrees in a polar orbit. ","c":"C.\tThey are in a geosynchronous orbit equally spaced around the equator. ","d":"D.\tThey are in eight orbital planes at an altitude of approximately 1,000 miles"}},{"num":587,"sample":"1P985","correct":"D","question":"How many satellites must be received to provide complete position and time? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1. ","b":"B.\t2. ","c":"C.\t3. ","d":"D.\t4"}},{"num":588,"sample":"1P986","correct":"B","question":"What is DGPS? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tDigital Ground Position System. ","b":"B.\tA system to provide additional correction factors to improve position accuracy. ","c":"C.\tCorrection signals transmitted by satellite. ","d":"D.\tA system for providing altitude corrections for aircraft"}},{"num":589,"sample":"1Q991","correct":"A","question":"Compliance with MPE, or Maximum Permissible Exposure to RF levels (as defined in FCC Part 1, OET Bulletin 65) for 'controlled' environments, are averaged over _______ minutes, while 'uncontrolled' RF environments are averaged over ______ minutes. ","answers":{"a":"A.\t6, 30. ","b":"B.\t30, 6. ","c":"C.\t1, 15. ","d":"D.\t15, 1"}},{"num":590,"sample":"1Q992","correct":"B","question":"Sites having multiple transmitting antennas must include antennas with more than _______% of the maximum permissible power density exposure limit when evaluating RF site exposure. ","answers":{"a":"A.\tAny. ","b":"B.\t5. ","c":"C.\t1. ","d":"D.\t12.5"}},{"num":591,"sample":"1Q993","correct":"D","question":"RF exposure from portable radio transceivers may be harmful to the eyes because: ","answers":{"a":"A.\tMagnetic fields blur vision. ","b":"B.\tRF heating polarizes the eye lens. ","c":"C.\tThe magnetic field may attract metal particles to the eye. ","d":"D.\tRF heating may cause cataracts"}},{"num":592,"sample":"1Q994","correct":"A","question":"At what aggregate power level is an MPE (Maximum Permissible Exposure) study required? ","answers":{"a":"A.\t1000 Watts ERP. ","b":"B.\t500 Watts ERP. ","c":"C.\t100 Watts ERP. ","d":"D.\tNot required"}},{"num":593,"sample":"1Q995","correct":"B","question":"Why must you never look directly into a fiber optic cable? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tHigh power light waves can burn the skin surrounding the eye. ","b":"B.\tAn active fiber signal may burn the retina and infra-red light cannot be seen. ","c":"C.\tThe end is easy to break. ","d":"D.\tThe signal is red and you can see it"}},{"num":594,"sample":"1Q996","correct":"C","question":"If the MPE (Maximum Permissible Exposure) power is present, how often must the personnel accessing the affected area be trained and certified? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tWeekly. ","b":"B.\tMonthly. ","c":"C.\tYearly. ","d":"D.\tNot at all"}},{"num":595,"sample":"1Q1001","correct":"D","question":"What device can protect a transmitting station from a direct lightning hit? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tLightning protector. ","b":"B.\tGrounded cabinet. ","c":"C.\tShort lead in. ","d":"D.\tThere is no device to protect a station from a direct hit from lightning"}},{"num":596,"sample":"1Q1002","correct":"C","question":"What is the purpose of not putting sharp corners on the ground leads within a building? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tNo reason. ","b":"B.\tIt is easier to install. ","c":"C.\tLightning will jump off of the ground lead because it is not able to make sharp bends. ","d":"D.\tGround leads should always be made to look good in an installation, including the use of sharp bends in the corners"}},{"num":597,"sample":"1Q1003","correct":"B","question":"Should you use a power drill without eye protection? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tYes. ","b":"B.\tNo. ","c":"C.\tIt's okay as long as you keep your face away from the drill bit. ","d":"D.\tOnly in an extreme emergency"}},{"num":598,"sample":"1Q1004","correct":"C","question":"What class of fire is one that is caused by an electrical short circuit and what is the preferred substance used to extinguish that type of fire? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tFE28. ","b":"B.\tFE29. ","c":"C.\tFE30. ","d":"D.\tFE31"}},{"num":599,"sample":"1Q1005","correct":"D","question":"Do shorted-stub lightning protectors work at all frequencies? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tYes. ","b":"B.\tNo, the short also kills the radio signals. ","c":"C.\tNo, the short enhances the radio signal at the tuned band. ","d":"D.\tNo, only at the tuned frequency band"}},{"num":600,"sample":"1Q1006","correct":"A","question":"What is a GFI electrical socket used for? ","answers":{"a":"A.\tTo prevent electrical shock by sensing ground path current and shutting the circuit down. ","b":"B.\tAs a gold plated socket. ","c":"C.\tTo prevent children from sticking objects in the socket. ","d":"D.\tTo increase the current capacity of the socket"}}]
